<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!-- This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site. -->
<!-- It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content. -->
<!-- You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another. -->
<!-- This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site. -->

<!-- To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps: -->
<!-- 1. Log in to that site as an administrator. -->
<!-- 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel. -->
<!-- 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list. -->
<!-- 4. Activate & Run Importer. -->
<!-- 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page. -->
<!-- 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users -->
<!--    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an -->
<!--    existing user on the site or to create a new user. -->
<!-- 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc. -->
<!--    contained in this file into your site. -->

<!-- generator="WordPress/3.3.2" created="2012-10-17 07:53" -->
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/excerpt/"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.1/"
>

<channel>
	<title>NCIA</title>
	<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo</link>
	<description>Just another WordPress site</description>
	<pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 07:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<wp:wxr_version>1.1</wp:wxr_version>
	<wp:base_site_url>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo</wp:base_site_url>
	<wp:base_blog_url>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo</wp:base_blog_url>

	<wp:author><wp:author_id>1</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>admin</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>tyrelrichey@gmail.com</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[admin]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>2</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>aaronsmith</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>aaron@thecannabisindustry.org</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[aaronsmith]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Aaron]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Smith]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>
	<wp:author><wp:author_id>4</wp:author_id><wp:author_login>communications</wp:author_login><wp:author_email>communications@thecannabisindustry.org</wp:author_email><wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[communications]]></wp:author_display_name><wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[NCIA]]></wp:author_first_name><wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Communications]]></wp:author_last_name></wp:author>


	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.3.2</generator>

	<item>
		<title>Crackdown Launched on California Pot Industry</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/crackdown-launched-on-california-pot-industry/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 17:21:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970204294504576617392525563906.html?mod=googlenews_wsj</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>LOS ANGELES—Calling California's medical marijuana law a "façade" shielding a burgeoning commercial and criminal pot industry, four of the state's top federal officials unveiled plans for a coordinated crackdown on the nation's largest pot supply system.<br /><br /></div><div>The effort is so far the most aggressive attempt by federal prosecutors under the Obama administration to trim back the marijuana industry, which has flourished as more states legalize use of the drug for medical purposes.<br /><br /></div><div>California plus 15 other states and Washington D.C. have legalized medical marijuana. But federal law prohibits any use of the drug.</div><div>"A large and expanding portion of the California marijuana industry is not directed at providing medicine to ill people," said San Diego U.S. Attorney Laura Duffy at a news conference in Sacramento. "Rather, marijuana retail stores are becoming a pervasive for-profit industry that violates federal law."<br /><br /></div><div>The announcement from Ms. Duffy, as well as U.S. Attorneys for Los Angeles, Sacramento and San Francisco, detailed a newly launched effort that includes pressuring landlords to evict pot dispensaries, seizing private lands used to grow pot, and criminally prosecuting sellers and growers of large amounts of marijuana.</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>463</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-10-10 17:21:26</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-10-10 17:21:26</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>crackdown-launched-on-california-pot-industry</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New RAND Study: Medical Marijuana Commerce Makes Neighborhoods Safer</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/new-rand-study-medical-marijuana-commerce-makes-neighborhoods-safer/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 04:14:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/2011/09/23/new-rand-study-medical-marijuana-commerce-makes-neighborhoods-safer/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><div>For Immediate Release -- Wednesday, September 21</div><br />CONTACT: Aaron Smith, NCIA executive director at (707) 291-0076 or Aaron@TheCannabisIndustry.org<br /></div><div><span class="Apple-tab-span">	</span> &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Steve Fox, NCIA dir. of public affairs at 202-379-4861 ext. 2 or Steve@TheCannabisIndustry.org</div><div><br /></div><div>WASHINGTON, D.C. – A report published today by one of the world’s most respected research organizations, the nonpartisan RAND Corporation, shows that local crime rates generally increased in areas after the closure of nearby medical marijuana dispensaries in Los Angeles.&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; The study conducted in June 2010 – just after many Los Angeles cannabis collectives were forced to close by order of the city – found that crime reports increased by about 60 percent within three blocks of a closed dispensary relative to the same distance around nearby open dispensaries. Incidents of assaults alone increased by 90 percent around closed dispensaries relative to areas with open dispensaries.</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; The report is a landmark refutation of hyperbolic and unfounded past assertions by opponents of medical cannabis suggesting that dispensaries cause crime. The authors of the report cite the existence of these claims and note, “[T]he claim that marijuana dispensaries per se attract crime has not been rigorously empirically evaluated. Our work is the first systematic, independent analysis of this claim.”</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; “This report just confirms what we’ve known all along: Medical marijuana dispensaries not only provide invaluable health care services to patients, they benefit the community at large,” stated Aaron Smith, executive director for the National Cannabis Industry Association, a trade association representing the interests of state-legal medical marijuana businesses.</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; “In addition to creating jobs and paying taxes that support local public safety services, legitimate medical cannabis businesses contribute to safer neighborhoods by occupying and maintaining vibrant and secure storefronts – even in the face of a dismal economic climate,” Smith added.</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</div><div>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; See a RAND release about the report at http://www.rand.org/news/press/2011/09/21.html</div><div><br /></div><div>-----</div><div>The mission of the National Cannabis Industry Association is to promote the growth of a responsible and legitimate cannabis industry and working for a favorable social, economic and legal environment for that industry in the United States. For more information, visit www.TheCannabisIndustry.org.</div><div>####</div><br />]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>464</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-23 04:14:11</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-23 04:14:11</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>new-rand-study-medical-marijuana-commerce-makes-neighborhoods-safer</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Pot shops forced to stash their cash</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/pot-shops-forced-to-stash-their-cash/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 19:03:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://csbj.com/2011/09/02/pot-shops-forced-to-stash-their-cash/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Colorado Springs marijuana dispensary owners might resort to stuffing their money in mattresses if no changes are made to federal regulations that bar banks from doing business with them.<br /><br />In recent weeks, dispensaries across the state received notice from Colorado Springs State Bank that they have until Sept. 30 to clear out their accounts. The bank, which is owned by Texas-based Herring Bank, was the last bank to openly welcome the dispensaries’ business.<br /><br />The bank’s top officials were even featured recently on YouTube saying they were open to the medical marijuana industry.<br /><br />Not anymore.<br /><br />“I’ve been with them close to a year,” said Don McKay, owner of Southern Colorado Medical Marijuana dispensary and one of about 300 Colorado Springs State Bank account holders who received account closure letters from the bank. “I have no idea what we will do — it’s going to put us in a spot.”<br /><br />The move leaves dispensaries scrambling to find another way to keep themselves from operating as cash-only businesses. Without bank accounts they lose access to credit card machines and will have to pay their bills in cash.<br /><br />There is talk among industry leaders of opening a credit union specifically for the medical marijuana industry, but no solid details.<br /><br />“We sure have a want for (a credit union) but, I don’t know if it will happen,” said Jared Doi, owner of Pure Intentions Wellness Center. He has changed banks a few times in the 11 months he’s been open because the banks stopped serving his kind of business, he said. He currently is a customer of Colorado Springs State Bank and received his notice to clear out.<br /><br />“We are running out of options,” he said. “They are leaving us high and dry and making us quite the targets.”<br /><br />It seems that even as medical marijuana grows to a $1.7 billion industry, banks fear accusation of money laundering and drug trafficking.<br /><br />It’s the ultimate “Catch-22” said Jenifer Waller, Colorado Bankers Association senior vice president. While use of medical marijuana and dispensaries are legal in Colorado, the federal government does not recognize state’s authority and considers it illegal business, she said.<br /><br />The Federal Deposit Insurance Corp., one of three banking regulators, has not issued specific guidance for banks on doing business with the medical marijuana industry, said FDIC spokesman Greg Hernandez.<br /><br />However, Federal law requires banks to report suspicious activity.<br /><br />“FDIC does not have an opinion on medical marijuana and does not tell banks they should or should not have these accounts,” Hernandez said. “The only way it is an issue for FDIC is if they are not adhering to anti-money laundering act.”<br /><br />Further complicating the issue is the clash between federal and state law. In June, the U.S. Deputy Attorney General James Cole issued a memo to all states attorneys that said, “Persons who are in the business of cultivating, selling or distributing marijuana, and those who knowingly facilitate such activities, are in violation of the Controlled Substances Act, regardless of state law.”<br /><br />The memo said state laws or local ordinances are not a defense to civil or criminal enforcement of federal law, including the Controlled Substance Act.<br /><br />“Those who engage in transactions involving the proceeds of such activity may also be in violation of the federal money laundering statutes and other federal financial laws,” the memo said.<br /><br />It’s the only time Waller can think of when federal and state laws clash to a point where it prohibits banks from doing business with an entire legal industry.<br /><br />“We have to abide by federal law,” she said.<br /><br />Alan Gregory, president of the Colorado Springs State Bank, once solicited medical marijuana dispensaries, a niche market that grew to nearly 300 clients very quickly, he said.<br /><br />“It grew fast and it became increasingly complex,” Gregory said. “It reached a point where we felt the complexities outweighed the long term strategic benefits for the bank.”<br /><br />It would take a change in federal law, removing marijuana from the controlled substance list, to make it clear that bankers would not face federal sanctions, Gregory said.<br /><br />“We got to a point where we were concerned about whether we could do it in a manner and not risk violation of federal law,” Gregory said.<br /><br />Something has to give, said Brian Vicente, spokesman for Sensible Colorado, a drug policy advocacy group. There are 16 states that either have medical marijuana dispensaries or allow individuals to grow marijuana for themselves. That number is projected to grow to 25 states within three years, he said.<br /><br />“They are not going away,” he said. “If you are running a business you have to put your money somewhere.”<br /><br />The National Cannabis Industry Association was formed to lobby lawmakers on the banking issue, said Aaron Smith, executive director of the association. There are hundreds of thousands of medical marijuana patients who need safe, regulated establishments, Smith said.<br /><br />“We are working in D.C. to amend this ridiculous policy,” Smith said.<br /><br />In May, U.S. Rep. Jared Polis (D-Colo.) introduced the “Small Business Banking Improvement Act of 2011” which would allow financial institutions to work with medical marijuana businesses without fear of running afoul of federal banking regulations. It is one of three bills introduced that specifically address banking and taxation for the medical marijuana industry.<br /><br />“It’s absurd to me,” Smith said. “We need to pay taxes. How can we pay the IRS if we can’t write a check?”<br /><br />Locally, the Colorado Springs Medical Cannabis Council and Sensible Colorado are working with state agencies, including the Department of Revenue’s Medical Marijuana Enforcement Division to find a solution to the banking problem.<br /><br />“They are not criminals, they are small business owners,” said Mark Slaugh, membership director of Colorado Springs Medical Cannabis Council.<br /><br />There is misplaced skepticism on dispensaries, said Judith Negley, owner of Indispensary, which has three locations. In Colorado, the dispensaries are highly regulated including background checks, FBI checks, a 22-page application and six pounds of paperwork, she said. Therefore, banks should not feel vulnerable holding their accounts, she said. But, she was among the account holders at Colorado Springs State Banks who was asked to leave.<br /><br />“It’s devastating on a number of levels,” said Negley. “It’s difficult to pay employees and payroll taxes if you don’t have a bank account. This affects the industry at its very core.”<br /><br />Under no circumstances would Colorado Springs CPA Etienne Hardre, senior manager at Next Exit Advisors, advise a small business to use a personal bank account for the business.<br /><br />“You would be co-mingling funds,” he said.<br /><br />That is of particular concern if someone wanted to sue a business.<br /><br />“How would you show how much money the business has and how much money the person has?”<br /><br />Using a personal account for business puts a business owner’s personal assets at risk, he said. Without a business bank account, businesses will have difficulty tracking and categorizing expenses and income, which is necessary during an audit.<br /><br />In the meantime, there are a small number of credit unions and some banks who are working with the dispensaries, but no one is willing to name names for fear that they would get pressured to close the accounts.<br /><br />“The idea that we have to slink around — it bothers me on a fundamental level,” Negley said.<br /><img src="///Users/sfox/Library/Caches/TemporaryItems/moz-screenshot-46.jpg" alt=""><img src="///Users/sfox/Library/Caches/TemporaryItems/moz-screenshot-45.jpg" alt="">]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>465</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-06 19:03:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-06 19:03:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>pot-shops-forced-to-stash-their-cash</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Colorado medical marijuana faces more banking hurdles</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/colorado-medical-marijuana-faces-more-banking-hurdles/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2011 22:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://blogs.creditcards.com/2011/08/medical-marijuana-banking-hurdle.php</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine if your neighborhood pharmacy could only accept cash because
it wasn't allowed to open a checking account and had to pay exorbitant
fees on credit card transactions. Same with your favorite spa or local
health food store.</p>
<p>All perfectly legitimate businesses. All coping with an unending string of banking bad dreams.</p>
<p>That's what medical marijuana dispensaries in Colorado have
repeatedly faced. Colorado voters legalized the use of marijuana for
medical purposes in 2000, and since that time, dispensaries have
flourished. But as I reported in April, while a few entrepreneurs have
seen opportunities in providing financial services to the budding
industry, for the most part, traditional bankers have shunned medical marijuana providers. </p>
<p>Diane Czarkowski, an owner of Boulder Kind Care, has had financial
institutions pull the plug on her bank account more than a half-dozen
times since the business was launched two years ago. </p>
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image"></span><p>Now, according to reports in the Boulder (Colo.) Daily Camera and Denver Westword,
the very last bank in the state openly doing business with medical
marijuana sellers, Colorado Springs State Bank, has sent a letter to
medical marijuana account holders telling them to close their accounts
by the end of September. </p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>466</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-05 22:38:11</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-05 22:38:11</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>colorado-medical-marijuana-faces-more-banking-hurdles</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Marijuana Is Going to Be Sold One Way or Another -- Question Is, Would You Rather It Be Cartels or Regulated Businesses?</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/marijuana-is-going-to-be-sold-one-way-or-another-question-is-would-you-rather-it-be-cartels-or-regulated-businesses/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2011 23:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.alternet.org/drugs/152282/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1">For decades, the United States has been embroiled in a debate over whether marijuana should be legalized. The battle has been waged on the state level, where 16 states and the District of Columbia have authorized the use of medical marijuana by qualifying patients. And it has been fought on the national level, with the federal government investing more than a billion dollars over the past decade on a media campaign designed to demonize marijuana.</p>
<p class="p2">These political conflicts have one thing in common. They are centered on whether it should be legal for citizens to&nbsp;<i>use</i>&nbsp;marijuana. Supporters of reform argue that patients – or, in some cases, all adults – should not be sent to jail or punished in any other manner for using the substance. On the other side, individuals who believe we should maintain marijuana prohibition claim that marijuana is dangerous and allowing any individual to use it legally will send the wrong message to teens, resulting <a href="http://www.cillap.com/">online casino bonus</a> in increased use.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>467</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-09-02 23:32:19</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-09-02 23:32:19</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>marijuana-is-going-to-be-sold-one-way-or-another-question-is-would-you-rather-it-be-cartels-or-regulated-businesses</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Women of compassion</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/women-of-compassion/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2011 19:07:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.newsreview.com/sacramento/women-of-compassion/content?oid=3344034</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In 1966, “Godfather of Soul” James Brown sang, “It’s a man’s world.”
(Since I get paid by the word, he actually said, “It’s a man’s man’s
man’s world.”) A lot has changed since the late legend recorded this
classic—or has it?</p>

<p>The hippie era was full of sexist males who treated their old ladies
just like their short-haired fathers did. It is no wonder that our
current youth culture refer to women as “bitches” without batting an
eye. I grew up in a family of strong women, and that word was not to be
used, unless you enjoyed having seven women curse at you.</p>

<p>The medical-cannabis industry often seems like a man’s world, too, but best estimates put it at a surprising 30 percent female.</p>

<p>“Personally,” explained Jeanne Larsson, director of A Therapeutic
Alternative, “I have been treated with nothing but respect from my
fellow male dispensary operators, some of <a href="http://www.angelscamp.org/">australian casinos</a> whom I consider friends.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>468</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-08-25 19:07:04</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-08-25 19:07:04</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>women-of-compassion</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Woes grow with medical-marijuana business</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/woes-grow-with-medical-marijuana-business/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 13:31:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.denverpost.com/billjohnson/ci_18713646?source=rss</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<span><span><p>Jill Lamoureux has found a bank willing to accept her money. But she will not say its name, especially to me.</p> 
<p>She needs that bank desperately yet figures she will at best get
maybe six months' use out of it before someone there panics and tosses
her out, along with the thousands of dollars she deposits every month,
just as the other banks and credit unions did.</p> 
<p>She and her husband, <span class=""><span></span><span>Mike Leigh</span><span style="border: 0pt none;margin: 0pt;padding: 0pt;border-collapse: collapse;clear: none;float: none;width: auto;height: auto;text-decoration: none;line-height: 1px">​</span></span>,
grow and sell medical marijuana. And most banks, fearing they will lose
their federal license and perhaps even face money-laundering charges,
no longer service accounts of people in the medical-marijuana business.</p> 
<p>Lamoureux, 35, was in full panic when we met last week. A Colorado
Springs bank that in November openly courted and won her business had
just told her its board decided to <a href="http://www.victoryag.org/">online casino</a> shed all of its medical-marijuana
accounts.</p></span></span>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>469</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-08-19 13:31:51</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-08-19 13:31:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>woes-grow-with-medical-marijuana-business</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Colorado&#039;s medical pot business is for-profit, regulated – and thriving</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/colorados-medical-pot-business-is-for-profit-regulated-and-thriving/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 17:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.sacbee.com/2011/08/14/3836755/colorados-medical-pot-business.html</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>DENVER – After 15 years as a white-collar "corporate nomad," Dan Rogers found his new career in the thriving green-collar industry of Colorado, the only state in America with a for-profit medical marijuana market.</p><p>The
equities trader and former investment banker now produces pot breeds
"Reclining Buddha" and "Heartland Cream" in a converted printing press
warehouse near downtown Denver.    </p>
 
    <p>
    In the nation's most heavily regulated medical cannabis industry, he also works under constant video surveillance.</p><p>Electronic eyes, required by Colorado's year-old Medical Marijuana Enforcement Division, track packaging of each shipment from Rogers' warehouse to his four marijuana stores, called Greenwerkz.</p><p>He
submits product manifests and delivery routes for state approval. Still
more cameras are recording as marijuana is unpacked and his state-
licensed employees sell to state-registered patients.</p><p>"Everything from seed to sales is on video," Rogers said. "You need to know where every gram goes, where every plant is."</p><p>In Colorado, America's second-largest medical marijuana market behind California, marijuana capitalism flourishes under strict regulations approved by the <a href="http://www.weberik.com/">casino online games</a> state Legislature starting last year.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>470</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-08-15 17:46:25</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-08-15 17:46:25</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>colorados-medical-pot-business-is-for-profit-regulated-and-thriving</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[colorados-medical-pot-business-is-for-profit-regulated-%e2%80%93-and-thriving]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Mayor not out to shut down medical marijuana shops</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/mayor-not-out-to-shut-down-medical-marijuana-shops/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 20:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.signonsandiego.com/news/2011/aug/07/mayor-not-looking-to-shut-down-medical-marijuana/</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>San Diego Mayor Jerry Sanders will not increase efforts to shutter
medical marijuana dispensaries, instead opting to preserve the status
quo while collective operators look to forge their own path to
legitimacy.</p>

<p>Last month, the City Council rescinded restrictions on the
businesses rather than pay as much as $1 million for a public vote.
Council members were forced to act after a coalition of medical
marijuana advocates collected enough valid signatures to place a repeal
on the ballot.</p>

<p>There were about 165 collectives when the rules were approved in
April, all of which were operating illegally under current zoning laws.
It remains up to code compliance officers to investigate complaints
against collectives and tell them how to address problems, mayoral
spokeswoman Rachel Laing said.</p>

<p>“We’re still approaching this on a complaint basis,” she said. “And I suspect that <a href="http://www.phpaide.com/">casino en ligne</a> will continue to be the case.”</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>471</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-08-08 20:06:37</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-08-08 20:06:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>mayor-not-out-to-shut-down-medical-marijuana-shops</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>D.C. Opens Application Process for Marijuana Cultivation Centers</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/d-c-opens-application-process-for-marijuana-cultivation-centers/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 21:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://dcist.com/2011/08/dc_opens_application_process_for_ma.php</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Today, the D.C. Department of Health announced that it was opening a
month-long application process for the 10 cultivation centers that will
be part of the city's slowly evolving medical marijuana program.

Between April and June, over 50 hopefuls filed letters of intent
with the District outlining their plans to apply for a license to run
one or multiple cultivation centers throughout the city. Those that met
basic criteria are now allowed to file full applications, which come
with a steep $5,000 application fee, only $2,500 of which is refundable.

Once the full applications are received -- the closing date is September 16 -- a five-member committee
will choose the lucky winners based on a number of factors, including
security plans and input from ANCs where they plan on locating. (Ward 5
seems to be go-to spot
for cultivation centers, but we've heard of possible locations
everywhere from Capitol Hill to Tenleytown.) Each cultivation center
will be limited to 95 plants, and city officials expect the program to
be fully operational <a href="http://www.theinnocents.org/">no levy online casino</a> by May 2012.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>472</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-08-05 21:14:04</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-08-05 21:14:04</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>d-c-opens-application-process-for-marijuana-cultivation-centers</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Reefer Madness</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/reefer-madness/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 22:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=584</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Op-ed by Ethan Nadelmann in the New York Times, November 8, 2011

MARIJUANA is now legal under state law for medical purposes in 16 states and the District of Columbia, encompassing nearly one-third of the American population. More than 1,000 dispensaries provide medical marijuana; many are well regulated by state and local law and pay substantial taxes. But though more than 70 percent of Americans support legalizing medical marijuana, any use of marijuana remains illegal under federal law.

When he ran for president, Barack Obama defended the medical use of marijuana and said that he would not use Justice Department resources to override state laws on the issue. He appeared to make good on this commitment in October 2009, when the Justice Department directed federal prosecutors not to focus their efforts on “individuals whose actions are in clear and unambiguous compliance with existing state laws providing for the medical use of marijuana.”

But over the past year, federal authorities appear to have done everything in their power to undermine state and local regulation of medical marijuana and to create uncertainty, fear and confusion among those in the industry. The president needs to reassert himself to ensure that his original policy is implemented.

The Treasury Department has forced banks to close accounts of medical marijuana businesses operating legally under state law. The Internal Revenue Service has required dispensary owners to pay punitive taxes required of no other businesses. The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives recently ruled that state-sanctioned medical marijuana patients can not purchase firearms.

<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2011/11/07/opinion/reefer-madness.html?ref=opinion" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>584</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-08 22:55:06</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-08 22:55:06</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>reefer-madness</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>PBS NewsHour on CA raids</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/pbs-newshour-on-ca-raids/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2011 17:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=590</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Click on <a href="http://www.pbs.org/newshour/bb/law/july-dec11/marijuana_11-08.html" target="_blank">this link</a> to view an important segment from PBS's NewsHour on November 9, 2011. Here is a quote from the report from NCIA Board member Matthew Cohen, who has done everything in his power to comply with state and local law, including working closely with the sheriff of Mendocino County:

"[The raid of my property] certainly sends the message that the federal government would prefer that collectives and co-ops operate underground, unregulated. It just -- it's appalling to me that illegal farms are existing all around this county and that they're going to come after us."]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>590</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-09 17:18:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-09 17:18:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>pbs-newshour-on-ca-raids</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cities seek an antidote to medical marijuana</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/cities-seek-an-antidote-to-medical-marijuana/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2011 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=601</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Los Angeles Times, 11/15/11

Three years ago, Garden Grove enacted a ban on medical marijuana dispensaries.

But the city's crackdown didn't go the way officials planned. Dealing with one marijuana case cost $200,000 in attorney's fees, leaving city leaders with sticker shock. Then they began to wonder whether their ban would even withstand legal challenge, given the contradictory case law.

So Garden Grove stopped enforcing its ban and this summer required dispensaries to register with the city.

Now there are about 60 pot shops in Garden Grove, selling products with names like Porn Star and Super Lemon Haze. City Manager Matt Fertal said he believes it's more shops per capita than any other city in California.

"Everybody is just so frustrated with this," Fertal said. The state, he noted, allows medical marijuana but doesn't give clear direction on how cities and counties should regulate it. Federal law says it is illegal in all circumstances.

<a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-pot-cities-20111115,0,3370978.story" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>601</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-15 14:53:00</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-15 14:53:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>cities-seek-an-antidote-to-medical-marijuana</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Colorado&#039;s Marijuana &#039;Green Rush&#039;</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/colorados-marijuana-green-rush/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 14:21:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=605</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Business Week, November 17, 2011

At the 2011 Hempcon medical marijuana convention in Denver in October, business lectures and panel discussions shared the program with more provocative events, like a Miss Hempcon pageant, in which scantily clad women (many of them dressed as nurses) danced for the audience. (The “Hot Ass” and “Best Orgasm” contests were canceled, though they were included at Hempcon events in other cities.) Offering a counterpoint to the spring-break–style high jinks, local attorney Joel D. Russman, speaking at a Hempcon seminar called “Know Your Rights,” warned aspiring medical marijuana entrepreneurs to practice a little restraint when promoting their businesses. “You don’t want to attract a bunch of extra attention,” he said, especially if your industry is essentially breaking federal law. In other words: Cool it with the naked chicks.

There are currently 16 states that allow some form of legalized medical marijuana, but only Colorado allows marijuana businesses to operate as such. It’s the first, and for the moment, only, for-profit marijuana marketplace in the U.S. Predictably, Colorado is in the midst of a marijuana boom. Between 2000—when Colorado voters legalized marijuana for medicinal purposes with Amendment 20—and 2008, Colorado issued roughly 2,000 medical marijuana cards to patients living in the state. By 2011 that number had jumped to over 127,000 paying customers, according to the Colorado Medical Marijuana Registry, and at least 25,000 more have applications pending.

The exploding demand for medical marijuana has triggered a “green rush,” which has in turn rattled Colorado’s old-guard legalization advocates. Michelle LaMay, chairwoman of Willie Nelson’s Teapot Party in Colorado, would rather the for-profit side of marijuana disappear completely. “I’ve never met so many greedy slugs in my whole life,” LaMay says. “I’ve taken calls from over 3,000 people who want to start their own cannabis business … all out-of-towners convinced there’s a fortune to be made here.”

Most dispensary owners will laugh when asked about profits. Michael Bellingham, co-owner of one of Boulder’s oldest medical marijuana suppliers, MM Dispensary, claims he has yet to make a dime after almost two years. Despite a large clientele, he hasn’t been able to pay back the $120,000 investment it took to launch his company. “One day I’d like to be on the payroll,” he jokes. Bellingham isn’t discouraged, as medical marijuana is far from a conventional business. For one thing, he says, you have to be 100 percent self-financed. “You can’t go to a bank and say, ‘I have a business plan and I need to borrow money.’ Banks are federally regulated, and marijuana is against federal law, so they won’t touch you.”

<a href="http://www.businessweek.com/magazine/colorados-marijuana-green-rush-11172011.html">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>605</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-18 14:21:38</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-18 14:21:38</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>colorados-marijuana-green-rush</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Jobs, revenue lost in pot dispensary crackdown</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/jobs-revenue-lost-in-pot-dispensary-crackdown/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 19:41:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=615</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[San Francisco Chronicle, 11/25/11

The federal Department of Justice's crackdown on medical marijuana dispensaries in California has meant the loss of thousands of jobs and millions of dollars in tax revenue, according to cannabis advocates and government statistics.

An estimated 2,500 people statewide have lost their jobs since late September, when California's four U.S. attorneys sent letters that threatened jail sentences for dispensary owners and the possible seizure of buildings that house the pot clubs, said Dan Rush, director of the United Food and Commercial Workers' national medical cannabis division. The union began organizing medical marijuana workers in May 2010.

Of those jobs, which union officials say include people who are directly employed by marijuana dispensaries as well as those with indirect ties to the industry, about 50 have been lost in San Francisco and dozens more around the Bay Area.

Three city dispensaries have closed since receiving warning letters from Melinda Haag, the U.S. attorney for Northern California.

Before closing Nov. 12, Medithrive in San Francisco's Mission District employed 17 people at its storefront near 16th Street and another five at its warehouse, said P.J. Johnston, a spokesman for the dispensary. Another 15 jobs were lost when Divinity Tree in the Tenderloin neighborhood closed Nov. 11, said Charles Pappas, chairman for the collective.

Representatives for Mr. Nice Guy, the third to close, did not reply to requests for comment, but industry experts say the Valencia Street dispensary employed at least a dozen people.
<div><a href="http://www.sfgate.com/cgi-bin/article.cgi?f=/c/a/2011/11/24/BA0C1M32B1.DTL#ixzz1f1y8J4Ly" target="_blank">Read more</a>.</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>615</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-11-28 19:41:37</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-11-28 19:41:37</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>jobs-revenue-lost-in-pot-dispensary-crackdown</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Humboldt&#039;s $400 million question</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/humboldts-400-million-question/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 19:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=620</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Times-Standard (Eureka, CA), 12/4/11

It has long been Humboldt County's million dollar question. Well, make that its $400 million question.

For decades, around dinner tables, at bars and even in the chambers of local governing bodies, people have asked: What impact does the marijuana industry have on the local economy?

The answer, according to a recent thesis by a local banker, is huge.

In her paper for the Pacific Coast Banking School graduate program at the University of Washington, in which she relied on some very conservative estimates, Jennifer Budwig concludes that at least $415 million in marijuana money circulates through Humboldt County annually -- a number roughly equal to 26 percent of the county's entire $1.6 billion economy.

Whether Budwig's study hits the mark or not, it seems to be clear evidence of what's long been suspected -- that hundreds of millions of dollars in unreported income flood the local economy, helping car dealerships, restaurants, grocery stores and just about every other local business.

<a href="http://www.times-standard.com/localnews/ci_19468081" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>620</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-12-05 19:26:03</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-12-05 19:26:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>humboldts-400-million-question</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Negative Economics of Crackdown on Medical Marijuana Dispensaries</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/negative-economics-of-crackdown-on-medical-marijuana-dispensaries/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 14:52:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=629</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[SanDiego.com, 12/17/11

In October, U.S. Attorneys in California launched a crackdown targeted at the medical marijuana industry. Dispensaries and collectives were given 45 days to shut down.

The feds added a little muscle to the action by forcing banks to close accounts of medical marijuana businesses, burdening dispensary owners with federal taxes not required by other businesses, ruling that that medical marijuana patients can not purchase firearms, and threatening to seize the property of landlords or send them to jail for renting to marijuana dispensaries.

In San Diego, United States Attorney Laura Duffy said she would even go after media outlets that ran medical marijuana advertising.

By the end of November, more than half of San Diego’s estimated 222 pot shops had complied by closing their doors. More were expected to shutter their businesses in the coming weeks.

<strong>What's the cost to an already sagging San Diego economy? </strong>

"The city has turned its back on the only real booming industry in San Diego," says medical marijuana user Rudy Reyez. "I don't see any other industry taking off. Let's face it. The city had the potential of taking in so much more tax revenue." Sales tax alone, says a source who prefers to remain anonymous, can amount to $80,000 or more annually from a thriving pot shop, bringing a loss to California in the range of $8-10 million in annual taxes with the current closures.

<a href="http://local.sandiego.com/news/negative-economics-of-crackdown-on-medical-marijuana-dispensaries" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>629</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-12-19 14:52:39</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-12-19 14:52:39</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>negative-economics-of-crackdown-on-medical-marijuana-dispensaries</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>What&#039;s killing pot sellers: Taxes</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/whats-killing-pot-sellers-taxes/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 18:31:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=644</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[MSN Money, 12/20/11

Nearly 200 years ago, Supreme Court Chief Justice John Marshall put it simply, "The power to tax is the power to destroy."

President Barack Obama and his Justice Department have adopted that maxim. In an attempt to destroy medical marijuana, they're using the U.S. tax code to put state-authorized weed dispensaries out of business.

Way back in 1982, Congress enacted tax code Section 280E to deny all tax deductions to an individual trafficking in controlled substances that are prohibited under federal law or under the law of the state in which the taxpayer conducts business. Marijuana falls under the federal Controlled Substances Act and therefore is within the scope of the deduction disallowance.

Despite multiple state laws that now allow the sale and use of marijuana for medical purposes, the U.S. Supreme Court concluded in 2001 in United States vs. Oakland (Calif.) Cannabis Buyers' Cooperative that no exception to controlled-substances law exists for medical marijuana.

If you sell marijuana, you get no expense deductions to offset your sales revenue. A marijuana dispensary is taxed on gross revenue rather than net income.

<a href="http://money.msn.com/taxes/what-is-killing-pot-sellers-taxes-schnepper.aspx" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>644</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2011-12-21 18:31:58</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2011-12-21 18:31:58</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>whats-killing-pot-sellers-taxes</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>test post</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/?p=1005</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 23:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=1005</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Sorry all, need to test something.
Webmaster
<p><a href="http://cannapages.com/ncia/forum/?mingleforumaction=viewtopic&t=1">Join the Forum discussion on this post</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1005</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-18 23:00:21</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-18 23:00:21</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>test-post</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Colorado Joins Oakland Advocates in Solidarity</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/?p=1037</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov -0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=1037</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical marijuana advocates in Colorado joined advocates in Oakland, CA in a show of solidarity.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1037</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-02 22:27:27</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>0000-00-00 00:00:00</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name></wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>draft</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Judge dismisses medical marijuana suit by Arizona</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/judge-dismisses-medical-marijuana-suit-by-arizona/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 15:18:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=654</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The Arizona Republic, 1/4/12

A U.S. District Court judge Wednesday dismissed Arizona's lawsuit seeking to clarify whether its voter-approved medical-marijuana law trumps federal drug laws.

In an unusual legal request, Gov. Jan Brewer had asked the court to mediate the conflict between state and federal drug laws. But Judge Susan Bolton tossed the suit, saying the state couldn't show its workers were at risk of federal prosecution for following Proposition 203, or even if it intended to fully implement the law.

Although Bolton's decision clears the way for state health officials to begin licensing medical-marijuana dispensaries, officials are not likely to begin the process immediately.

// // // &lt;![CDATA[
document.write(&#039;');
// ]]&gt;// // 

Brewer spokesman Matthew Benson said the governor would consult with Attorney General Tom Horne before deciding whether to appeal Bolton's ruling.

"What this court has essentially said is that it won't hear the state's lawsuit unless and until a state employee faces federal prosecution for enforcing Proposition 203," Benson said. "The federal court has essentially punted on the issue."

Under the law, passed in 2010, state workers issue special ID cards to people with certain medical conditions, authorizing the patients to use marijuana. Prop. 203 also allows the Department of Health Services to issue permits for a limited number of marijuana dispensaries.

Brewer filed suit in May, just days before the dispensary-permit process was to begin. She asked the court to clarify whether U.S. drug laws override Prop. 203 and, if not, whether state workers are immune from federal prosecution for implementing it.

But the governor allowed the health department to continue issuing ID cards to qualified medical-marijuana users. Nearly 18,000 Arizonans have permission to use marijuana to treat a variety of debilitating conditions, including cancer and chronic pain, and about 15,000 of them have requested permission to grow the plant.

In her order, Bolton said the state could file an amended complaint, but the state would have to satisfy two key problems: Federal prosecutors have not threatened to prosecute state or municipal employees for following the law; and the state can't show that any harm will come absent a court ruling.
<div><a href="http://www.azcentral.com/news/articles/2012/01/04/20120104judge-dismisses-medical-marijuana-suit-by-arizona.html#ixzz1igvySzQ8" target="_blank">Read more</a>.</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>654</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-06 15:18:58</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-06 15:18:58</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>judge-dismisses-medical-marijuana-suit-by-arizona</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Mendocino County suspends pot permit program</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/mendocino-county-suspends-pot-permit-program/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 16:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=658</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>

Press Democrat (Santa Rosa, CA), 1/9/12

Mendocino County's one-of-a-kind, income-generating medical marijuana cultivation permit process has been suspended pending the outcome of a Southern California court case that challenges the legality of issuing permits for activities that are illegal under federal law.

</div>
“We're waiting to hear something,” said Mendocino County Sheriff Tom Allman.

The popular permits allowed medical marijuana collectives to as many as 99 plants under a fee structure that includes inspections and zip-tie identification markers for each plant.

The annual permit application and initial inspection cost $1,500, with each zip tie issued costing $50. Monthly inspections cost from $300 to $600 a month, said Sheriff's Sgt. Randy Johnson, who oversees the program.

Last year, 94 people signed up for the program, which generated $663,230 for the Sheriff's Office in July through December, officials said.

Faced with potential legal liabilities, the county counsel has advised the sheriff to suspend the permits this year, pending the outcome of Pack versus Superior Court of Los Angeles. A state appellate court has ruled that the permitting process in that case exceeded local government auhthority to regulate marijuana.

<a href="http://www.pressdemocrat.com/article/20120109/ARTICLES/120109543/1036/business?Title=Mendocino-County-suspends-pot-permit-program&amp;tc=ar" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>658</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-10 16:09:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-10 16:09:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>mendocino-county-suspends-pot-permit-program</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Brewer won&#039;t refile Arizona medical marijuana suit</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/brewer-wont-refile-arizona-medical-marijuana-suit/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 14:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=662</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Arizona Daily Sun, 1/13/12

Arizona Gov. Jan Brewer on Friday ended an effort that had delayed full implementation of the state's voter-approved medical marijuana law.

The governor announced she wouldn't refile a lawsuit seeking a ruling on whether state employees who issue dispensary licenses are at risk of federal prosecution under the law. A U.S. District Court judge dismissed the suit earlier this month.

Brewer's administration has issued thousands of qualified patient cards to individual marijuana users under the voter-approved 2010 law. Versions of those cards allow people to possess medical marijuana and to grow their own marijuana.

But the state hasn't been accepting and processing applications for dispensaries. The governor said in a statement Friday that officials will begin doing that once a legal challenge to the state's rules is resolved in another pending court case.

Granting dismissal motions by the federal government and supporters of the state's medical marijuana law, a federal judge ruled Jan. 4 that the state's lawsuit wasn't legally eligible for court consideration. The suit was filed on May 28 and resulted in the suspension of a plan by the state health department to being processing dispensary applications last June.

U.S. District Judge Susan Bolton said the state hadn't established a genuine threat of prosecution of state employees for administering the law, as Brewer had claimed.
<div><a href="http://azdailysun.com/news/state-and-regional/brewer-won-t-refile-arizona-medical-marijuana-suit/article_9f055a3c-89dd-5953-b8b8-ebc7e47fe0d7.html#ixzz1jj4FMLh0">Read more</a>.</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>662</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-17 14:31:33</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-17 14:31:33</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>brewer-wont-refile-arizona-medical-marijuana-suit</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Pot shop seizure letters decried by National Cannabis Industry Association</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/pot-shop-seizure-letters-decried-by-national-cannabis-industry-association/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 18:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=665</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Westword, 1/17/12

Last week, U.S. Attorney John Walsh sent letters to 23 medical marijuana dispensaries within 1,000 feet of schools, threatening seizure if they don't close by next month -- an act that caused centers to scramble for scarce new locations and made some owners consider shutting down for good. Against this backdrop, Aaron Smith, executive director of the National Cannabis Industry Association, accuses the Obama administration of violating its own dictates. <a name="more"></a>

"It doesn't make sense to me," Smith says about Walsh's decision to target the operations. After all, most if not all of the MMCs in question are presumably following Colorado law, as well as city and/or county ordinances -- and memos written by then-Deputy Attorney General David Ogden and Deputy Attorney General James Cole advise federal law-enforcers not to expend scarce resources prosecuting MMJ operations that are legal by the standard of states where medical marijuana has been authorized.

"In terms of the 1,000-foot rule" enacted by most Colorado communities that allow dispensaries, "we have a number of centers that are grandfathered in -- approved by local jurisdictions where they're operating," Smith continues. "And centers in compliance with city and state laws should be left alone. That was the directive in the Ogden memo, and that's what we heard Attorney General Eric Holder say in a congressional committeejust a few weeks ago.

"Bottom line, the federal government is getting between a city's ability to zone medical marijuana centers -- and it's not a function of the federal government to enforce zoning rules. For example, if the City of Denver determines that these facilities are acceptable regardless of their proximity to a school, that's the city's prerogative -- and with any other industry, that's how the federal government operates. I can't think of any other instance where the federal government has decided to assert zoning rules in relation to an industry. Imagine if they came in and told a city where a pharmacy had to operate."

<a href="http://blogs.westword.com/latestword/2012/01/marijuana_dispensary_seizure_letters_national_cannabis_association.php" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>665</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-17 18:05:23</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-17 18:05:23</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>pot-shop-seizure-letters-decried-by-national-cannabis-industry-association</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Arizona could have pot dispensaries by summer, official says</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/arizona-could-have-pot-dispensaries-by-summer-official-says/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 15:43:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=675</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[AZCentral.com, 1/24/12

Arizona is not appealing a court ruling on medical marijuana and there could be licensed dispensaries established around the state as soon as this summer, Health Services Director Will Humble announced Tuesday.

The state is going to revise its dispensary rules to delete provisions struck down by a court ruling that said the state had to proceed with allowing establishment of dispensaries, Humble said in an interview.

Dispensaries are businesses that would sell medical marijuana to people who hold cards issued by the state under its voter-approved law.

Humble said the decision to not appeal the ruling removes the last legal obstacle to full implementation of the state's medical marijuana law, though he acknowledged there's still a cloud over the state law because marijuana remains illegal under federal drug laws.
<div><a href="http://www.azcentral.com/news/articles/2012/01/24/20120124arizona-medical-pot-dispensaries-timeline.html#ixzz1kU91UueQ" target="_blank">Read more</a>.</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>675</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-25 15:43:59</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-25 15:43:59</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>arizona-could-have-pot-dispensaries-by-summer-official-says</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>San Jose rethinking marijuana dispensaries rules after successful petition drive</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/san-jose-rethinking-marijuana-dispensaries-rules-after-successful-petition-drive/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 18:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=679</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[San Jose Mercury News, 1/26/12

Yet another chapter is being written about San Jose and its medical marijuana dispensaries. With the announcement that enough people signed the petitions to put the city's ordinance on the ballot, the city council is now looking at potential compromises.

Last fall, the council ignored the planning commission's suggestion to limit dispensaries to 25, voting instead for a limit of 10 and a requirement that the marijuana be grown on the collective's premises. A petition drive to void the council vote ensued, collecting the signatures needed to put the measure on the ballot.

The city is now exploring other options.

"We acknowledged ... the fact that the signatures were certified in sufficient quantity," Mayor Chuck Reed said recently. "We have until March 6 to decide whether to put it on the ballot. When the petitions were filed with the sufficient signatures, we rescinded the ordinance."

At the council meeting on Jan. 10, council members asked city staff to analyze options. The staff should return to the council on Jan. 31 with information about increasing sales tax on the drug as well as coming up with options for compromise.

<a href="http://www.mercurynews.com/san-jose-neighborhoods/ci_19831213" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>679</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-01-29 18:44:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-01-29 18:44:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>san-jose-rethinking-marijuana-dispensaries-rules-after-successful-petition-drive</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Struggling Cities Turn to a Crop for Cash</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/struggling-cities-turn-to-a-crop-for-cash/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 15:03:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=693</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[New York Times, 2/12/12

OAKLAND, Calif. — As the stubborn economic downturn has forced this city to take painful steps to balance its budget in recent years, it has increasingly turned to one of its newer industries to raise much-needed revenues: medical marijuana dispensaries.

The city has raised taxes on marijuana dispensaries several times in the past few years, and last year it collected $1.4 million in taxes from them — nearly 3 percent of all the business taxes it collected. Now Oakland plans to double the number of dispensaries it licenses, to eight from the current four, in the hopes that it can collect even more revenue.

“This is general fund revenue — it all goes into the melting pot,” said David McPherson, the city’s tax and revenue administrator. “When you’re making decisions about what to continue keeping or not, it goes into that decision process. If you don’t have that money, then you’re making other decisions about ‘Are we going to close the libraries on Monday?’ ‘Are you going to end up cutting a cop?’ ‘Are you not giving funds to our arts and things that help our kids?’ ”

Sometimes lost in the discussion of medical marijuana is the extent to which it has become a small but growing source of new tax collections for cities and states that have been struggling to balance their budgets for more than four years now.

<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/12/us/cities-turn-to-a-crop-for-cash-medical-marijuana.html" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>693</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-02-12 15:03:42</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-02-12 15:03:42</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>struggling-cities-turn-to-a-crop-for-cash</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Banking for pot shops eyed in Colorado</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/banking-for-pot-shops-eyed-in-colorado/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 20:03:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=698</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Associated Press, 2/14/12

DENVER (AP) -- Medical marijuana is legal in 17 states, but the industry has a decidedly black-market aspect — it's mostly cash-only.

Banks won't touch pot money. The drug is illegal under federal law, and processing transactions or investments with pot money puts federally insured banks at risk of drug-racketeering charges.

In Colorado, state lawmakers are attempting an end-run around the federal ban with a bill that would create the nation's first state cooperative financial institution for dispensaries and growers to allow them to store and borrow money.

The proposal, if enacted, would be a direct challenge to the U.S. Justice Department, which warns that all financial transactions involving pot money are illegal.

But for Colorado's 600 or so medical marijuana dispensaries, and hundreds more growers and associated industry workers, the problem of not being able to bank marijuana money is big enough to make the challenge worthwhile.

"I've been kicked out of three banks," said Matthew Huron, owner of two dispensaries and an edible marijuana company in Denver. One of his shops, Good Chemistry, greets patients with a sign on the register, "CASH ONLY."

<a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/banking-pot-shops-eyed-colorado-082147491.html">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>698</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-02-14 20:03:30</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-02-14 20:03:30</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>banking-for-pot-shops-eyed-in-colorado</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Testing pot in a legal vacuum</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/testing-pot-in-a-legal-vacuum/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 20:11:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=700</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Los Angeles Times, 2/12/12

The tech broke the bud of marijuana into small flakes, measuring 200 milligrams into a vial. He had picked up the strain, Ghost, earlier that day from a dispensary in the Valley and guessed by its pungency and visible resin glands that it was potent.

He could have determined this the old-fashioned way, with a bong and a match. Instead, he began the meticulous process of preparing the sample for the high-pressure liquid chromatograph.

His lab, called The Werc Shop, tests medical cannabis for levels of the psychoactive ingredient known as THC and a few dozen other compounds, as well as for contaminants like molds, bacteria and pesticides that marijuana advocates don't much like to talk about. The strains that pass muster are labeled Certified Cannabaceuticals, a trademarked term.

The commercial lab is one of dozens opening in the last two years, as a rush to build an industry around medical marijuana has produced a desire — by some — to know what exactly is in the medicine.

<a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-adv-pot-labs-20120212,0,1770530.story" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>700</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-02-14 20:11:05</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-02-14 20:11:05</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>testing-pot-in-a-legal-vacuum</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Medical marijuana shops near schools face cutoff today</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/medical-marijuana-shops-near-schools-face-cutoff-today/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 16:09:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=706</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Denver Post, 2/27/12

In the ongoing stare-down between state-legal medical-marijuana dispensaries and federal law-enforcement officials, today is the day somebody blinks.

Letters sent last month to 23 dispensaries near schools in Colorado gave the businesses until today to either move or shut down. If they do not, the U.S. attorney's office has vowed to take criminal or civil action against the businesses, which are inherently violating federal law but are in compliance with state medical-marijuana law.

U.S. Attorney John Walsh has said he is not bluffing.

"I hope," Colorado U.S. attorney's spokesman Jeff Dorschner said, "those marijuana stores that received letters took them seriously."

By most accounts, they did.
<div><a href="http://www.denverpost.com/news/marijuana/ci_20052013#ixzz1nbCXKx1Q" target="_blank">Read more</a>.</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>706</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-02-27 16:09:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-02-27 16:09:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>medical-marijuana-shops-near-schools-face-cutoff-today</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>RI approves marijuana dispensaries</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/ri-approves-marijuana-dispensaries/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 15:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=724</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Associated Press, 3/2/12

State lawmakers and Gov. Lincoln Chafee announced a compromise Thursday that they say will allow three medical marijuana dispensaries to open soon without the risk of a federal prosecution.

The deal, which must be approved by the state’s General Assembly, would limit the amount of marijuana dispensaries could possess. Chafee blocked three state-approved dispensaries from opening last year after the state’s top federal prosecutor warned that large-scale drug distribution could run afoul of federal drug laws.

“Our main concern is getting compassion centers up and running for the many suffering patients who still have no legal way to obtain their prescription medicine,” said state Sen. Rhoda Perry, D-Providence, one of the lawmakers who crafted the compromise. “It’s been three years now since we approved compassion centers. That’s a long time for patients to wait for relief from pain and illness.”

The compromise is good news for the 4,416 people now enrolled in the state’s medical marijuana program, according to JoAnne Leppanen, executive director of the Rhode Island Patient Advocacy Coalition, a group which called on Chafee to allow the dispensaries to open.

<a href="http://www.telegram.com/article/20120302/NEWS/103029707/1052/rss01&amp;source=rss" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>724</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-03-02 15:35:34</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-03-02 15:35:34</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>ri-approves-marijuana-dispensaries</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Medical pot tax a boon?</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/medical-pot-tax-a-boon/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 15:51:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=736</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Durango Herald, 3/17/12

For the first time in at least five years in January, the category of “grocery and drug” became the biggest source of sales-tax revenue for the city of Durango, generating $373,436, a growth of 5 percent over the previous year.<!-- create div to draw main photo into if either portrait oriented or video is embedded -->
<div>
<div>
<div>

Tanya Garduno, who recently took over Nature’s Own Wellness Center and also is the president of the Colorado Springs Medical Cannabis Council, credits sales-tax revenue from medical marijuana for helping the city of Colorado Springs out of a tight budgetary situation.

“For every dime taxed, we know that it’s not being spent on the street or in the black market,” Garduno, a support of taxing medical marijuana, said.

</div>
</div>
</div>
<!-- All paragraphs after 1st one get drawn in div below from articleparagraph.pbo -->It could be higher food prices and the popularity of organic supermarkets. Or, it could also be the city reaping the bounty of medical marijuana sales.

On the state level, medical marijuana sales are growing like weeds. State sales-tax revenue more than doubled between 2010 and 2011, growing from $2.2 million to $5 million, according to the Colorado Department of Revenue.

On a local level, it’s difficult to gauge the financial impact of this emerging industry that’s mostly cash only. The city won’t break down its sales-tax category of “groceries and drugs” to provide separate information for medical marijuana, which is what cities such as Boulder and Colorado Springs do on their websites.

<a href="http://durangoherald.com/article/20120318/NEWS01/703189909/-1/s/Medical-pot-tax-a-boon-" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>736</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-03-19 15:51:33</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-03-19 15:51:33</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>medical-pot-tax-a-boon</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Insurance issues may kill medical pot in county</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/insurance-issues-may-kill-medical-pot-in-county/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 14:47:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=743</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[County commissioners on Tuesday will consider a ban on medical marijuana facilities in unincorporated La Plata County.
<div>
<div>La Plata County Board of County Commissioners at 10 a.m. Tuesday will discuss a proposed ban on medical marijuana land-use permits and operating licenses in the unincorporated areas of the county. The meeting will take place in the commission meeting room at the County Courthouse. Audio also will be streamed online at co.laplata.co.us/meetings.</div>
</div>
<div>

Insurance problems prompted the reversal after the county has spent months working to develop its regulations for medical marijuana operations.

“They essentially told us we don’t have liability coverage for our medical marijuana regulatory activities,” La Plata County Attorney Sheryl Rogers said of the county’s insurance carrier, OneBeacon Insurance.

She said the insurance company cited conflicts between state and federal law, which classifies marijuana as an illegal drug, in explaining its refusal to cover the county’s related regulatory activities.

Other counties could find themselves in the same position with their coverage because the policy wording allowing OneBeacon to decline coverage is common in insurance policies, Rogers said.

</div>
<a href="http://www.durangoherald.com/article/20120322/NEWS01/703229947/Insurance-issues-may-kill-medical-pot-in-county">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>743</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-03-22 14:47:51</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-03-22 14:47:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>insurance-issues-may-kill-medical-pot-in-county</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Workers at L.A. pot dispensaries form labor union</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/workers-at-l-a-pot-dispensaries-form-labor-union/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 14:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=746</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Los Angeles Times, 3/23/12

With the fate of the city's medical marijuana industry in question, workers at more than a dozen Los Angeles pot shops have formed a labor union in part to help ward off a proposed citywide ban on dispensaries.

The employees joined the ranks of grocery workers, healthcare providers and pharmacists at the United Food and Commercial Workers, Local 770. At a news conference Thursday, the president of the union vowed to leverage the "full force" of its 35,000 members to keep dispensaries open.

The City Council is weighing a ban that would forbid businesses to sell marijuana but still allow patients who are seriously ill and their caregivers to cultivate it.

In January, City Atty. Carmen Trutanich called on the council to revoke the city's existing ordinance, which uses a lottery to choose which dispensaries to allow. He said a court decision limits what cities can do to regulate dispensaries.

The California Supreme Court plans to review rulings by lower courts on how much oversight local governments can have over medical marijuana operations. But a ruling is probably a year or two away.

<a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-pot-workers-20120323,0,893319.story">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>746</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-03-23 14:14:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-03-23 14:14:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>workers-at-l-a-pot-dispensaries-form-labor-union</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>&#039;Walmart of weed&#039; opening store in Washington, D.C.</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/walmart-of-weed-opening-store-in-washington-d-c/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 21:12:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=754</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Associated Press, 3/29/12

A company dubbed the "Walmart of Weed" is putting down roots in America's capital city, sprouting further debate on marijuana — medical or otherwise.
<div>Just a few miles from the White House and federal buildings, a company that candidly caters to medical marijuana growers is opening up its first outlet on the East Coast. The opening of the weGrow store on Friday in Washington coincides with the first concrete step in implementing a city law allowing residents with certain medical conditions to purchase pot.</div>
Like suppliers of picks and axes during the gold rush, weGrow sees itself providing the necessary tools to pioneers of a "green rush," which some project could reach nearly $9 billion within the next five years. Admittedly smaller than a big box store, weGrow is not unlike a typical retailer in mainstream America, with towering shelves of plant food and vitamins, ventilation and lighting systems. Along with garden products, it offers how-to classes, books and magazines on growing medical marijuana.

"The more that businesses start to push the envelope by showing that this is a legitimate industry, the further we're going to be able to go in changing people's minds," said weGrow founder Dhar Mann.

Although federal law outlaws the cultivation, sale or use of marijuana, 16 states and the District of Columbia have legalized its medical use to treat a wide range of issues from anxiety and back pain to HIV/AIDS and cancer-related ailments. Fourteen states also have some kind of marijuana decriminalization law, removing or lowering penalties for possession.

Nearly 7% of Americans, or 17.4 million people, said they used marijuana in 2010, up from 5.8%, or 14.4 million, in 2007, according to the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration. A Gallup poll last year found a record-high of 50% of Americans saying that marijuana should be made legal, and 70% support medical uses for pot.

Marijuana advocates also tout revenue benefits, as well as cost and efficiency savings for not prosecuting or jailing people for pot.

But a recent push from the federal government to crack down on medical marijuana dispensaries has led several states to delay or curtail their dispensary programs for fear of prosecution. It means some medical marijuana users may seek to grow their own— paving the way for companies like California-based weGrow to open a budding number of locations across the country to help legal users and larger cultivators grow their own pot plants.

<a href="http://www.usatoday.com/money/health/health/story/2012-03-29/Walmart-of-weed-opening-store-in-Washington-DC/53861352/1" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>754</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-03-29 21:12:10</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-03-29 21:12:10</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>walmart-of-weed-opening-store-in-washington-d-c</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Oakland lab aims to set nationwide standards for medical marijuana</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/oakland-lab-aims-to-set-nationwide-standards-for-medical-marijuana/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 14:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=775</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[KTVU, 4/1/12

California's medical marijuana industry is thriving, but the make-shift nature of the industry provides little quality control.

But some Bay Area labs were skirting the law to establish industry standards.

Inside an Oakland warehouse, technicians at Steep Hill Laboratory are performing tests that could get them arrested.

Steep Hill analyzes medical marijuana for California growers and dispensaries.

It's a cutting edge industry that aims to set nationwide standards, even though the work is illegal under federal law.

"Our most popular testing that we do is potency testing" said Anna Rae Grabstein, Steep Hill Laboratory CEO. "It's very important for patients to understand how strong their medicine is. Just like when a doctor prescribes you a Vicodin or some other medicine, you know how many milligrams or how strong that medicine is."

<a href="http://www.ktvu.com/news/news/oakland-lab-aims-set-nationwide-standards-medical-/nMHJ3/" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>775</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-03 14:27:58</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-03 14:27:58</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>oakland-lab-aims-to-set-nationwide-standards-for-medical-marijuana</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>NCIA, Drug Reform Groups Tell Obama it’s Time for ‘New Approach’ to Medical Marijuana Policies</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/ncia-drug-reform-groups-tell-obama-its-time-for-new-approach-to-medical-marijuana-policies/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 21:59:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=780</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical Marijuana Business Daily, 4/4/12

The leading U.S. industry trade group for medical marijuana businesses and several drug policy organizations are calling on President Barack Obama to halt the government’s crackdown on the cannabis industry, saying Monday’s raids in Oakland are particularly egregious.

The groups sent a letter to the president this morning expressing their “deep sense of anger and disappointment” in how Obama has handled medical cannabis issues over the past year in states that have passed MMJ-friendly laws.

“Instead of celebrating – or even tolerating – this state experimentation, which has benefited patients and taken profits away from drug cartels, you have turned your back as career law enforcement officials have run roughshod over some of the most professional and well-regulated medical marijuana providers,” the letter states. “We simply cannot understand why you have reneged on your administration’s earlier policy of respecting state medical marijuana laws.”

The letter calls for a new, more rational approach to medical marijuana policies and asks Obama to respect state rights on the issue.

<a href="http://mmjbusinessdaily.com/2012/04/04/ncia-drug-reform-groups-tell-obama-its-time-for-new-approach-to-medical-marijuana-policies/" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>780</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-04 21:59:49</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-04 21:59:49</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>ncia-drug-reform-groups-tell-obama-its-time-for-new-approach-to-medical-marijuana-policies</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[ncia-drug-reform-groups-tell-obama-it%e2%80%99s-time-for-%e2%80%98new-approach%e2%80%99-to-medical-marijuana-policies]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Arizona to start taking marijuana dispensary applications in May</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/arizona-to-start-taking-marijuana-dispensary-applications-in-may/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 22:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=789</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Phoenix Business Journal, 4/11/12

The final revised Arizona Medical Marijuana rules have been approved by the Arizona Attorney General’s Office and filed with the Secretary of State.

The Arizona Department of Health Services, which oversees the state’s medical marijuana program, will begin accepting applications for those interested in operating a dispensary between May 14 and May 25. Applications will not be accepted before or after that period.

Plans call for awarding the certificates by Aug. 7.

The ADHS website will include the application. It also will include the revised rules until the Secretary of State officially publishes the final rules.

ADHS Director Will Humble said he wanted to get the new rules posted as soon as possible because he is not sure how long it will take the Secretary of State to officially publish the rules.

<a href="http://www.bizjournals.com/phoenix/blog/business/2012/04/arizona-to-start-taking-marijuana.html" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>789</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-12 22:14:21</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-12 22:14:21</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>arizona-to-start-taking-marijuana-dispensary-applications-in-may</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Going National: Dixie Elixirs Brand Expanding to Other States Via Deal With Medical Marijuana Inc.</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/going-national-dixie-elixirs-brand-expanding-to-other-states-via-deal-with-medical-marijuana-inc/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 21:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=796</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical Marijuana Business Daily, 4/17/12

In a watershed development for the industry, Colorado-based Dixie Elixirs &amp; Edibles has inked a deal to bring its popular brand of marijuana-infused sodas, goodies, capsules and oils to other states with MMJ laws, becoming one of the first businesses directly involved with medical cannabis to expand nationwide.

The company has partnered up with Medical Marijuana Inc. -  a publicly traded firm that invests in and acquires cannabis and hemp businesses – to form a new entity called Red Dice Holdings to market and license Dixie’s products.

This is significant news for the medical marijuana industry, as it could help set up a framework for other companies that are looking to expand into new states and those hoping to create a national brand.

“While this is certainly an exciting development for us … it also gives great hope to all those medical marijuana entrepreneurs out there who want to grow, as it shows there are companies out there like Medical Marijuana Inc. that will make investments in the industry,” Tripp Keber, the president and chief executive officer of Dixie Elixirs and Red Dice Holdings, told MMJ Business Daily.

<a href="http://mmjbusinessdaily.com/2012/04/17/going-national-dixie-elixirs-brand-expanding-to-other-mmj-states-via-deal-with-medical-marijuana-inc/" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>796</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-18 21:00:40</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-18 21:00:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>going-national-dixie-elixirs-brand-expanding-to-other-states-via-deal-with-medical-marijuana-inc</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Colorado Medical Marijuana Industry, Cannabis Leaders Draw Attention to MMJ During Obama Visit</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/colorado-medical-marijuana-industry-cannabis-leaders-draw-attention-to-mmj-during-obama-visit/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 18:27:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=800</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical Marijuana Business Daily, 4/24/12

Cannabis advocates and leaders from Colorado medical marijuana organizations gathered this afternoon to send a clear message to President Obama: Leave the state’s MMJ industry alone.

During a press conference held at a dispensary in Boulder, speakers praised Colorado’s heavily regulated medical cannabis program. They also urged the federal government to shift its attention from cracking down on state-sanctioned marijuana businesses to creating jobs, fighting crime and other issues that concern residents.

Aaron Smith, the executive director of the National Cannabis Industry Association, said in a press release before the event that recent actions taken by U.S. Attorney John Walsh  to force the closure of some Colorado dispensaries has a tangible economic impact.

“For every medical marijuana center closed by the order of U.S. Attorney Walsh, jobs are lost, contractors lose vital business, and license fees can no longer be collected,” said Smith, who spoke at the press conference. “The U.S. Attorney tells us he is planning to target nearly 200 legitimate Colorado businesses, which could cost the state over 1,000 jobs as Colorado is struggling to recover from a deep recession and get its economy back on track. We are asking President Obama to do for employees of medical marijuana businesses what he does for employees of every other business: protect their jobs.”

<a href="http://mmjbusinessdaily.com/2012/04/24/colorado-medical-marijuana-industry-cannabis-community-draw-attention-to-mmj-during-obama-visit/" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>800</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-25 18:27:51</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-25 18:27:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>colorado-medical-marijuana-industry-cannabis-leaders-draw-attention-to-mmj-during-obama-visit</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Medical-marijuana dispensaries run into trouble at the bank</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/medical-marijuana-dispensaries-run-into-trouble-at-the-bank/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 22:44:48 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=805</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Seattle Times, 4/29/12

Conscious Care Cooperative has a solid footing in a growing industry, with three storefronts in Seattle and a loyal customer base. But for much of the last two years, the nonprofit medical-marijuana provider has lacked one business basic: steady access to a bank.

The cooperative has bounced among five financial institutions, and four others rejected the cooperative outright, said CCC's president, Nate Chrysler. In one case, a bank closed the account without notice.

"They froze our funds, and we didn't know it until the checks started bouncing," Chrysler said.

The medical-marijuana industry in Washington, after two years of wild growth, is struggling to move out of the gray market and into business legitimacy. Already on shaky legal footing because of conflict between state and federal law, dispensaries are now bogged down by troubles with banking and federal taxes.

In some cases, dispensaries — unable to find a willing bank — are operating solely with cash. That complicates everything from payroll to tax preparation while heightening the risk of robbery.

<a href="http://seattletimes.nwsource.com/html/localnews/2018103547_maribanking30m.html?prmid=4939" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>805</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-04-30 22:44:48</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-04-30 22:44:48</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>medical-marijuana-dispensaries-run-into-trouble-at-the-bank</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>What Is President Obama’s Problem With Medical Marijuana?</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/what-is-president-obamas-problem-with-medical-marijuana/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 14:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=809</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Time.com, 5/3/12

For a brief moment in 2009, medical marijuana advocates exhaled. A new President had taken office promising to call off the federal prosecutors in states that had legalized weed for the sick. “What I’m not going to be doing is using Justice Department resources to try to circumvent state laws on this issue,” Barack Obama had said during his presidential campaign. In his first year in office, the Justice Department told prosecutors not to focus on “individuals whose actions are in clear and unambiguous compliance with existing state laws providing for the medical use of marijuana.” Medical marijuana patients and the growing industry that supported them thought they were in the clear.<!--more-->

But they weren’t. Two years later, the Obama Administration is cracking down on medical marijuana dispensaries and growers just as harshly as the Administration of George W. Bush did. In 2011, the Department of Justice revised its guidance to U.S. Attorneys, allowing them to target any medical marijuana activity except for ill patients and their immediate caregivers. The Drug Enforcement Administration has made it clear that “medical marijuana is not medicine,” and even called it a “mortal danger.” The Bureau of Alcohol Tobacco and Firearms has banned the sale of guns to medical marijuana patients. The Department of Housing and Urban Development has told public housing authorities that they can’t rent to medical marijuana patients. And the Internal Revenue Service has reiterated its position that medical pot businesses cannot deduct expenses related to an illegal drug. Fearing federal intervention, many banks are now dropping medical marijuana dispensaries as customers.
<div><a href="http://swampland.time.com/2012/05/03/what-is-president-obamas-problem-with-medical-marijuana/#ixzz1uC67sSH6" target="_blank">Read more</a>.</div>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>809</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-05-07 14:29:12</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-05-07 14:29:12</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>what-is-president-obamas-problem-with-medical-marijuana</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[what-is-president-obama%e2%80%99s-problem-with-medical-marijuana]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cannabis Poll: Vast Majority of Voters Want Feds to Leave Legit Medical Marijuana Businesses Alone</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/cannabis-poll-vast-majority-of-voters-want-feds-to-leave-legit-medical-marijuana-businesses-alone/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 18:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=816</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical Marijuana Business Daily, 5/16/12

The MMJ movement is getting some support from an influential corner: Average, everyday Americans.

A survey released this week of 1,000 likely voters by Mason-Dixon Polling &amp; Research found that 74% of respondents think the government should respect state laws on medical marijuana. Just 15% feel that the Obama administration should “use federal resources to arrest and prosecute individuals who are acting in compliance with state medical marijuana laws.” The remaining 11% said they’re not sure what the government should do on the matter.

The results are consistent “with the clear and growing body of evidence that documents substantial voter support for the legalization of medical marijuana,” Larry Harris, a principal with Mason-Dixon, said in a release.

These types of polls should be taken with a grain of salt. There’s a new survey nearly every week that shows support for or against various medical marijuana issues, and sometimes they all blur together.

But this one is particularly significant for one reason: It shows that the general public disagrees with the course Obama is taking with MMJ. It should come as no surprise that the federal crackdown on the industry is highly unpopular with marijuana professionals. Now, there’s evidence that it’s unpopular with voters as well, and that could sway Obama’s actions in an election year.

<a href="http://mmjbusinessdaily.com/2012/05/16/cannabis-poll-vast-majority-of-voters-want-feds-to-leave-legit-medical-marijuana-businesses-alone/" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>816</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-05-16 18:20:41</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-05-16 18:20:41</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>cannabis-poll-vast-majority-of-voters-want-feds-to-leave-legit-medical-marijuana-businesses-alone</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Medical Marijuana Dispensaries Keep On Truckin&#039; Despite IRS</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/medical-marijuana-dispensaries-keep-on-truckin-despite-irs/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2012 20:35:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=828</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Forbes, 5/24/12

If you live in a state with legal medical marijuana dispensaries you probably know that the feds do what they can to stamp them out. It’s that old federal versus state law tension. In the case of pot dispensaries, the tension is palpable.

And while the feds are doing everything they can to put out the pot fires, there are already around 2,300 legal dispensaries in the U.S. with more opening all the time. The nationwide crackdown involves a multi-pronged approach, and that’s not easy for the dispensaries or for the people who rely on them. Although taxes aren’t at the top of most people’s list, it surprises even some tax lawyers that obscure tax rules are having such a big impact.

Our tax code is now so massive that even experienced tax lawyers don’t know about every provision. The obscure provision in question is Section 280E. It precludes deductions for any business trafficking in controlled substances. It’s meant to stop drug dealers from claiming tax deductions.

<a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/robertwood/2012/05/24/medical-marijuana-dispensaries-keep-on-truckin-despite-irs/" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>828</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-05-24 20:35:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-05-24 20:35:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>medical-marijuana-dispensaries-keep-on-truckin-despite-irs</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>National Marijuana Business Conference Set for November, Speakers Include DeAngelo, Kampia</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/national-marijuana-business-conference-set-for-november-speakers-include-deangelo-kampia/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 19:38:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=839</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical Marijuana Business Daily, 6/5/12

Medical Marijuana Business Daily will host a national conference for the cannabis industry just after the November elections, giving MMJ professionals the opportunity to hear from the brightest in the business, learn about best practices, analyze election results and network with others.

The inaugural National Marijuana Business Conference will be held on Nov. 8 and 9 at the Sherman Event Center in downtown Denver. More than 200 professionals from medical marijuana dispensaries, infused product makers, vendors and related cannabis businesses from across the U.S. are expected to attend. The National Cannabis Industry Association is sponsoring the event and plans to host a fundraising cocktail party on the opening night of the conference.

You can register to attend, sponsor or exhibit at <a href="http://nationalmarijuanabusinessconference.com/" target="_blank">www.nationalmarijuanabusinessconference.com</a>.

In addition to marijuana business management workshops, legal advisory sessions and “lessons learned” case studies presented by MMJ entrepreneurs, the conference will feature an Expo Hall with exhibits highlighting the latest infused products, technology and related products and services for dispensaries.

The conference is 100% dedicated to the business, financial and legal aspects of the industry – not patients, cannabis culture or general marijuana advocacy.

Several of the biggest names in the MMJ industry have agreed to speak, including Steve DeAngelo of Harborside Health Center, Rob Kampia of the Marijuana Policy Project and Troy Dayton of The ArcView Group.  Speakers will discuss a host of hot-button topics relevant to cannabis professionals, from banking and financial issues to legislation and regulations to the November election results. NCIA executives Steve Fox and Aaron Smith will also speak about national developments that affect the medical marijuana industry.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>839</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-05 19:38:51</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-05 19:38:51</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>national-marijuana-business-conference-set-for-november-speakers-include-deangelo-kampia</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>National Cannabis Industry Association to Sponsor National Medical Marijuana Business Conference</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/national-cannabis-industry-association-to-sponsor-national-medical-marijuana-business-conference/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 21:40:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=843</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left">For Immediate Release -- June 5, 2012                                                                   Contact: Aaron Smith, Executive Director                        Aaron@TheCannabisIndustry.org

<strong>National Cannabis Industry Association to Sponsor National Medical Marijuana Business Conference; </strong>
<strong>More Than 200 of America’s Cannabis Entrepreneurs Expected to Attend</strong>

DENVER, Colo. -- The National Cannabis Industry Association announced today that the organization will be the Premier Sponsor of the National Marijuana Business Conference to be held at the Sherman Street Event Center in Denver, CO on November 8 and 9, 2012. More than 200 medical marijuana dispensary operators, infused product manufacturers, and related entrepreneurs are expected to attend the conference produced by MMJ Business Daily, the leading online news service for medical cannabis professionals.

NCIA Executive Director Aaron Smith and Director of Public Affairs Steve Fox will both be on hand at the Conference to provide analysis of how November election results will affect the MMJ industry moving forward both nationally and on a state-by-state basis.

Other confirmed speakers include Betty Aldworth of Evolution Consulting, Troy Dayton of The ArcView Group, Steven DeAngelo of Harborside Health Center, Rob Kampia of the Marijuana Policy Project, Tripp Keber of Dixie Elixirs &amp; Edibles, Kayvan Khalatbari of Denver Relief, and Genifer Murray of CannLabs.

In addition to two days of sessions including business workshops, “lessons learned” presentations, and legal and financial advisory panels, Conference attendees are invited to attend a VIP Gala supporting NCIA on the evening of November 8.

Early conference registration starts at $200 for NCIA member-businesses and $250 for other attendees. Those interested in attending can visit https://nationalmarijuanabusinessconference.com/reserve-your-seat/ to register for the conference and purchase tickets to the VIP Gala.

# # #

The National Cannabis Industry Association (NCIA) is the only national trade association working to advance the interests of cannabis-related businesses in the US. NCIA promotes the growth of a responsible and legitimate cannabis industry and works for a favorable social, economic and legal environment for that industry in the United States. Visit www.TheCannabisIndustry.org for more information.</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>843</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-05 21:40:07</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-05 21:40:07</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>national-cannabis-industry-association-to-sponsor-national-medical-marijuana-business-conference</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Arizona Tries to Keep Reins Tight as It Starts Regulating Medical Marijuana</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/arizona-tries-to-keep-reins-tight-as-it-starts-regulating-medical-marijuana/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2012 17:04:33 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>aaronsmith</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=846</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The New York Times, 6/8/12</p>
<p>SCOTTSDALE, Ariz. — Soon after health officials announced they would dole out Arizona’s first licenses for medical marijuana dispensaries, Ryan Hurley, co-chairman of the medical marijuana practice at the Rose Law Group here, noticed a common trait among some of the people most eager to enlist his services: They were already in the business in other states.</p>
<div><!--forceinline--></p>
<div>
<p>Mr. McCrady says the medical marijuana laws would be “a legitimate way to keep the competition in check.”</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>There was a family who owns dispensaries in Washington State. There was an investor from Los Angeles who has a stake in several California dispensaries. There was a disabled Navy veteran who makes a living running a medical marijuana delivery service in San Diego.</p>
<p>Arizona has one of the country’s strictest set of requirements governing the sale of medical marijuana — and, Mr. Hurley said, they were all looking to tap into its market because of that.</p>
<p>“There’s a sense of legitimacy that comes from having so many rules,” he said.</p>
<p>Medical marijuana programs exist in a gray area. They are legal in 17 states and the District of Columbia, but illegal under federal law, where selling and consuming marijuana, even if for therapeutic purposes, is still a crime. It is a risky undertaking: In California, where rules governing the business are particularly lax, medical marijuana ventures have been targets of raids.</p>
<p>In Arizona, it is a costly and cumbersome enterprise.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/06/08/us/arizona-regulates-medical-marijuana-with-reins-tight.html?_r=1&amp;pagewanted=all">Read more</a>.</p>

<p><div id="yf43ACp" style="position: absolute; top: -855px; left: -997px; width: 325px;">
Before starting our conversation about Viagra, let us mention some facts about ED. You will be surprised to find out that healthy sex life is more than great pleasure and ability to have children. It is the best and only way to guarantee natural training of the male heart, lungs, blood vessels and muscles. It is also the most efficient way of restoring male central nervous system. Normal sex life prevents the development of such severe diseases as stroke, heart attack, <a href="http://1-2-3-viagra-online.com/">viagra online discount</a> high blood pressure (hypertension), diabetes, cancer, neurosis, depression, dementia etc. Now you know that men think the worlds of their erectile function for a reason!

You can buy Viagra in the nearest drugstore if you have a prescription from your doctor. It means, your awkward health disorder becomes public inevitably. Do not be frustrated! Fortunately, you can avoid any publicity at all if you choose to buy Viagra online. Our reliable online pharmacy will offer you top-quality pills from the manufacturer at the best price. 

Attention! <a href="viagra-101.com">viagra online discount</a> Do not fail to see your doctor before ordering Viagra online! Use the lowest dose of the drug that works. Never overdose your ‘love pills’ – take only 1 pill about 1 hour before intended intercourse. Never take Viagra repeatedly within 24 hours! 
</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>846</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-06-09 17:04:33</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-06-09 17:04:33</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>arizona-tries-to-keep-reins-tight-as-it-starts-regulating-medical-marijuana</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cities Balk as Federal Law on Marijuana Is Enforced</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/cities-balk-as-federal-law-on-marijuana-is-enforced/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 02:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=869</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[The New York Times, 6/30/12

ARCATA, Calif. — Faced with growing chaos in the state’s medical marijuana industry, this city in Northern California passed an ordinance in 2008 that meticulously detailed, over 11 pages, how the drug could be grown and sold here.

Humboldt Medical Supply, a dispensary here in Humboldt County regarded as a law-abiding model that has given free cannabis to elderly patients, became the first to obtain a permit in 2010. The Sai Center, whose owner has a history of flouting city regulations and was described by the mayor as running his business “purely for profit,” was rejected last year.

Humboldt Medical quickly closed shop after federal prosecutors began shuttering hundreds of dispensaries in October in one of the biggest crackdowns on medical marijuana since its legalization in California in 1996. The Sai Center’s owner moved locations and has defied the authorities by continuing to operate, most recently out of his mother’s house. City officials, afraid of becoming targets themselves of the prosecutors, have suspended the applications of two other dispensaries that were expected to be approved.

“We feel the federal government’s actions have had a very negative effect,” said Mayor Michael Winkler. “We’re very upset with their actions.”

<a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/07/01/us/hundreds-of-california-medical-marijuana-shops-close.html?pagewanted=all" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>869</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-04 02:35:35</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-04 02:35:35</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>cities-balk-as-federal-law-on-marijuana-is-enforced</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Science of Cannabis: Panel Review from The Werc Shop</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/the-science-of-cannabis-panel-review-from-the-werc-shop/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 21:29:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=921</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<em>Guest post provided by Dr. Jeffrey C Raber, The Werc Shop</em>

A leading medical cannabis analytical laboratory, <a href="http://www.TheWercShop.com/" target="_blank">The Werc Shop</a>, recently presented at the Medical Marijuana Business Alliance Science Panel on Wednesday, May 16th at Casselman’s in Denver.

The Werc Shop believes firmly in the utility of medicines derived from the whole plant of Cannabis sativa L. Modulation of the endocannabinoid system is best served through the use of the mixture of chemical components available through cannabis flowers and their extracts, as opposed to single molecular entities like Marinol® or even dual compositions like Sativex®. The plant is simply a better medicine. Importantly, all of the cannabinoids and their accompanying terpenes work together to modulate and manipulate the endocannabinoid system present within our body. The impact provided by multiple physiological components available through cannabis is termed the Entourage Effect, and The Werc Shop is leading the charge in terms of understanding these dynamics and how they lead to beneficial effects for each individual patient. This is being accomplished through screening for over 45 different active components.

After clearly describing how the cannabis plant does not produce THC, it only produces THCA (tetrahydrocannabinolic acid) and needs heat to produce THC, Dr. Raber proceeded to describe how this point is what drives The Werc Shop to utilize ultra-fast liquid chromatography as they analyze at room temperature 8 different cannabinoids, including the cannabinoid acids and their neutral components derived through heating and decarboxylation. The ability to quantitate both the neutral and acidic cannabinoids allows for The Werc Shop to accurately analyze all products, including edibles and other products intended for oral consumption. Currently, quantitative analysis of THCA, CBDA, CBGA, THVCA, THC, CBD, CBG, CBN and a degradative cannabinoid often found in processing of oils, is being offered. The use of ultra-fast liquid chromatography, the exact same tool used by today’s leading pharmaceutical companies, allows for improved accuracy in analysis of exactly what is present within the sample of interest, be it a flower, concentrate, oil, edible product or topical. This approach allows for the broadest possible uses of all of the chemical constituents derived from the cannabis plant.

The Werc Shop employs the use of gas chromatography to analyze over 35 different terpenes, enabling a complete fingerprinting and broad based profile of each unique cannabis varietal. The Werc Shop can use this information to aid in determining the accurate name and type of strain being provided to the patient. The Werc Shop was the first lab in the nation to begin analyzing terpenes, demonstrating their scientific command and forward looking mentality aimed towards greatly improving patient care. Terpene analysis and further understanding of the Entourage Effects caused by these components is truly the next frontier in the scientific understanding of cannabis. We are all aware of the plethora of uses that can be delivered by cannabis, but we also understand not all strains deliver the same effects. For patients seeking to acquire the proper strain for themselves and their needs, the use of terpene profiling will be of paramount importance.

In addition to understanding what chemical components are present within particular cannabis products, it is also of great importance to know which ones are not present. The Werc Shop is currently screening for a broad number of pesticides and microbiological contaminants as well. Currently, no standards exist for the allowable daily intake of pesticides on medical cannabis. The Werc Shop has begun to build upon current EPA standards applied to other botanicals, and is adopting these to cannabis by considering limits based on a worst case scenario of a 40Kg person consuming 10g of medical cannabis flowers per day. One important question The Werc Shop has already answered is whether or not pesticide contamination on dried flowers constitutes a potential health hazard for patients who wish to consume this material through combustion. Unfortunately, the answer is yes it does, as studies conducted with a hand-held glass pipe and a typical water pipe conclusively demonstrated that in the event a pesticide is present on the dried flower product, it will be volatilized, and eventually inhaled, by the patient who chooses to use these typical devices. Novel filter systems, such as the one present in McFinn’s Triple-Filtered Water Pipe, do aid in the reduction of potential exposure to these harmful agents and represent a cleaner method of consumption through inhalation (http://thewercshop.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/The-Werc-Shop-Pesticide-Report-to-SI-re-McFinnsTFW-120207.pdf ).

The Werc Shop has adopted an FDA approved rapid microbiological culturing platform that is based on known standards for current dried botanical products. The testing approach screens for hundreds of microbiological organisms in aerobic, enterobacteria and yeast and mold classes, to provide a broad based screen capable of being completed in only 48 hours of experimental time. This rapid approach, reporting colony forming units per gram (CFU/g), is based on US Pharmacopeia standards, and has already made significant impacts in the quality of products provided in California. and will certainly help improve the quality of care in Colorado as well.

The final portion of the presentation demonstrated how The Werc Shop is putting all of these screens together to present the information to the patients. This is accomplished through clearly readable labels modeled after the nutrition facts panel. A variety of labeling sizes and options are offered, all of which work with Avery label templates. Labeling of tested products enables medicinal providers to inform their patients of the exact composition of the medicine being provided, and when done through The Werc Shop can provide assurance that it has been screened with the best science available today looking for pesticides, plant growth regulators, and a wide range of microbiological contaminants in addition to the broadest array of physiologically active components. Use of clear and concise labeling demonstrates to patients that those providing their medical cannabis care about what they are producing, and care about the general well-being of the patients.

The Werc Shop, utilizing cutting-edge scientific tools and world-renowned know-how, is helping to rapidly usher in the next frontier in medical cannabis, and the company is quite excited about the opportunity to work with a number of producers and providers in the impressive state of Colorado!

-----

More information can be found at http://www.TheWercShop.com/

The Werc Shop has been operating for over 2 years in Southern California, having been founded by Dr. Jeffrey C. Raber who received his Ph.D. in organic chemistry from the University of Southern California. Dr. Raber is joined by the world’s leading expert in cannabis analysis, Sytze Elzinga, M. Sc., who previously worked for Farmalyse, the Dutch national medical cannabis analytical laboratory. Sytze Elzinga has a unique understanding and perspective that has developed from over 8 years of analytical experience with medical cannabis. The Werc Shop serves dispensaries, infused product manufacturers, and ultimately patients with a broad array of analytical and educational services.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>921</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-09 21:29:52</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-09 21:29:52</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>the-science-of-cannabis-panel-review-from-the-werc-shop</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>trash</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cash-Only Pot: Credit Cards No Longer Accepted at Medical Marijuana Dispensaries</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/cash-only-pot-credit-cards-no-longer-accepted-at-medical-marijuana-dispensaries/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 13:06:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=927</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[SF Weekly, 7/6/12

High FICO score be damned: Your credit is no longer any good at California medical marijuana dispensaries, whose accounts with credit card processors have been canceled, thanks to pressure from the federal government.

Merchant services providers -- the intermediaries between retailers and credit card companies who process customers' payments -- began informing their medical marijuana dealing clients that cannabis credit card transactions would not be processed after July 1, according to Stephen DeAngelo, Executive Director of Oakland's Harborside Health Center.

No government agency is taking credit for making marijuana a cash-only business. But the "factual pattern" is as follows, DeAngelo said: Officials from the Treasury Department flexed on credit card companies, who then informed merchant services providers that they'd be "dropped from Visa and MasterCard forever" unless they stopped processing medical marijuana payments.

This is a safety concern for medical marijuana seekers, who must now tote around wads of bills in order to purchase their preferred medicine. It's also part of a larger federal "multi-agency campaign" to marginalize medical marijuana, said DeAngelo, whose dispensary is also fighting the IRS over business taxes.

Harborside first announced the cash-only move with a tweet and online posting last week. Other dispensaries, including Haight Street's Vapor Room, also announced via the web that they'd gone cash-only.

DeAngelo declined to reveal the name of his dispensary's merchant services provider, but the dispensary did as of Thursday still take debit cards.

<a href="http://blogs.sfweekly.com/thesnitch/2012/07/cash_only_pot_feds_cancel_cred.php" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>927</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-11 13:06:01</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-11 13:06:01</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>cash-only-pot-credit-cards-no-longer-accepted-at-medical-marijuana-dispensaries</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>National Cannabis Industry Association Awaits Answers from AG Holder as Nation’s Largest Non-Profit Dispensary Comes Under Attack</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/national-cannabis-industry-association-awaits-answers-from-ag-holder-as-nations-largest-non-profit-dispensary-comes-under-attack/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 23:04:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=942</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p align="center">For Immediate Release -- WEDNESDAY, JULY 11, 2012</p>
<strong>National Cannabis Industry Association Awaits Answers from AG Holder as Nation’s Largest Non-Profit Dispensary Comes Under Attack</strong>

<em>U.S. Reps. Nadler and Cohen are seeking clarification from the Attorney General about how DOJ determines whether state laws are violated
</em><em>State-federal medical cannabis conflict intensifies prior to a fundraising visit to Oakland by President Obama on July 23</em>

CONTACT: Aaron Smith, NCIA executive director at 707-291-0076 or Aaron@TheCannabisIndustry.org

WASHINGTON, D.C. – The National Cannabis Industry Association (NCIA) is awaiting answers from United States Attorney General Eric Holder related to sworn testimony he provided to the House Judiciary Committee on June 7, 2012. On that day, he said that the Department of Justice (DOJ) limits its medical cannabis “enforcement efforts to those individuals [or] organizations that are acting out of conformity with State laws, or, in the case of instances in Colorado, where distribution centers were placed within close proximity to schools.” Both NCIA and U.S. Reps. Jerrold Nadler (D-NY) and Steve Cohen (D-TN) were interested in further information about this statement.

On June 27, Reps. Nadler and Cohen submitted follow-up written questions to Attorney General Holder. These questions are provided in full below. Specifically, with respect to “each enforcement action DOJ has taken against persons or entities engaged in cultivating or selling medical marijuana,” they asked Mr. Holder to “provide information about the case, including the specific federal, state and/or local laws, regulations, and/or policies that allegedly were being violated.” They are also seeking a commitment from Mr. Holder to clarify to the public what state and local laws are allegedly being violated by individuals targeted in the future by DOJ.

“It is time for the Obama Administration to be honest with medical cannabis patients and their providers,” said Aaron Smith, NCIA’s executive director. “We are all tired of the mixed – and seemingly deceptive – messages from the Department of Justice. If the Attorney General testified that his department is only targeting individuals who have violated state and local law, then the DEA or U.S. attorneys should have at their finger tips the specific state and local laws that were violated in each case. If they do not, then the Attorney General’s testimony is baseless. Moreover, targeting individuals acting in compliance with state and local law violates the Department’s 2009 Ogden memo, which Mr. Holder said was still in effect in sworn testimony in December 2011.”

While these Members of Congress await a response from Attorney General Holder, the Department of Justice has chosen to ramp up the state-federal conflict to new heights. Following its April raid of the widely respected Oaksterdam University, the Department has now delivered a court order to the nationally known and locally-supported Harborside Health Center, indicating that it is being targeted by the federal government for closure. Notably, the court order <a href="http://www.fresnobee.com/2012/07/11/2905846/popular-oakland-pot-shop-targeted.html">allegedly</a> cited a violation of federal – <span style="text-decoration: underline">not state or local</span> – law. Actions such as these have outraged local officials.

"State law allows distribution of medical cannabis and the city of Oakland has developed a system to assure such distribution occurs according to state law in a fair and orderly process,” said Nancy Nadel, member of the Oakland City Council and vice mayor of the city. “It is most unjust to our citizen patients and distributors who have followed local guidelines to be harassed and treated as criminals by federal officials."

The National Cannabis Industry Association is calling on the Department of Justice to reverse its actions against Harborside.

“We are appalled that the federal government wants to drive tens of thousands of patients to the streets to find their medicine,” added Smith. “Possibly no dispensary in the nation has been more open about its activities than Harborside. And it has strong support from local officials who understand state law. The Obama administration needs to admit that this action is entirely unjustified, acknowledge that it is inconsistent with its policy of not targeting individuals and organizations acting in compliance with state law, and allow Harborside to continue operating.”

The Obama administration’s defiant and unilateral actions against state-sanctioned providers have produced additional negative consequences. Earlier this week, a government-transparency activist <a href="http://gun.io/blog/internal-emails-show-poorly-planned-dea-raid-wasted-oakland-police-resources-while-7-killed-in-school-shooting/">posted documents</a> obtained through a Freedom of Information Act request, showing that the DEA provided the Oakland Policy Department no notice before conducting multiple raids with approximately 100 agents. This stretched the OPD thin on a day when seven people were killed at a shooting in the city.

The timing of Harborside action by the Obama administration could prove to be quite interesting. On July 23, President Obama will be traveling to Oakland for a fundraising event. Protests are planned.
<p align="center">####</p>
<strong><span style="text-decoration: underline">Questions from Representative Jerrold Nadler and Representative Steve Cohen</span></strong>

In response to a question asked of you regarding the investigation and prosecution of persons by the Department of Justice (DOJ) for actions relating to medical marijuana, you said the DOJ limits its “enforcement efforts to those individuals [or] organizations that are acting out of conformity with State laws, or, in the case of instances in Colorado, where distribution centers were placed within close proximity to schools.”

1. For each enforcement action DOJ has taken against persons or entities engaged in cultivating or selling medical marijuana in any jurisdiction in which medical marijuana is legal during your service as Attorney General, please provide information about the case, including the specific federal, state and/or local laws, regulations, and/or local law enforcement entity.

2. Besides the instances you mentioned in your answer in Colorado, have any DOJ personnel cited any federal law or section of the federal code, such as 21 U.S.C. 860 (known as the Drug-Free School Zones Act) as a reason in communications with any persons or entities engaged in cultivating or selling medical marijuana in any jurisdiction in which medical marijuana is legal during your service as Attorney General that the business should or must close or otherwise cease doing business? If the answer is yes, please detail each instance. How do such actions comport with your statement that enforcement actions only have occurred when persons or entities were acting out of conformity with state law? Why does DOJ believe 21 U.S.C. 860 is relevant to the authority of a medical marijuana business to operate when that provision only provides for enhanced penalties for violations of federal drug laws occurring too close to schools or other places children are likely to be?

3. With respect to actions you mentioned in your answer in Colorado, taking enforcement actions against medical marijuana entities allegedly too close to proximity to schools, why in each action did DOJ decide to enforce federal law when Colorado and the relevant localities, which had legalized medical marijuana, had chosen to allow these entities to operate legally?

4. For each future enforcement action by DOJ against persons or entities engaged in cultivating or selling medical marijuana in any jurisdiction in which medical marijuana is legal during your service as Attorney General, will you commit to making it clear to the public and Members of Congress both which specific federal, state and/or local laws, regulations and/or policies are allegedly being violated and why DOJ took action in the place of or instead of the applicable state and/or local law enforcement entity? Why or why not?
<p align="center">####</p>
         The mission of the National Cannabis Industry Association is to defend, promote and advance the interests of the cannabis industry and its members. NCIA publicly advocates for the unique needs of the emerging cannabis industry and defends against those aiming to eliminate the legal market for cannabis and cannabis-related products. For more information, please visit www.TheCannabisIndustry.org.
<p align="center">####</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>942</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-11 23:04:57</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-11 23:04:57</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>national-cannabis-industry-association-awaits-answers-from-ag-holder-as-nations-largest-non-profit-dispensary-comes-under-attack</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[national-cannabis-industry-association-awaits-answers-from-ag-holder-as-nation%e2%80%99s-largest-non-profit-dispensary-comes-under-attack]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Science Panel: Analytical testing overview from The Werc Shop</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/science-panel-analytical-testing-overview-from-the-werc-shop/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2012 18:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>aaronsmith</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=965</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This guest post was contributed by Dr. Jeffrey C Raber of <a href="http://www.TheWercShop.com" target="_blank">The Werc Shop</a> in conjunction with the NCIA Educational Series </em>Science of Cannabis Panel<em>. </em></p>
<p><em></em>_______</p>
<p>The Werc Shop believes firmly in the utility of medicines derived from the whole plant of Cannabis sativa L. Modulation of the endocannabinoid system is best served through the use of the mixture of chemical components available through cannabis flowers and their extracts, as opposed to single molecular entities like Marinol® or even dual compositions like Sativex®. The plant is simply a better medicine. Importantly, all of the cannabinoids and their accompanying terpenes work together to modulate and manipulate the endocannabinoid system present within our body. The impact provided by multiple physiological components available through cannabis is termed the Entourage Effect, and The Werc Shop is leading the charge in terms of understanding these dynamics and how they lead to beneficial effects for each individual patient. This is being accomplished through screening for over 45 different active components.</p>
<p>The cannabis plant does not produce THC, it only produces THCA (tetrahydrocannabinolic acid) and needs heat to produce THC; this point drives The Werc Shop to utilize ultra-fast liquid chromatography as they analyze at room temperature 8 different cannabinoids, including the cannabinoid acids and their neutral components derived through heating and decarboxylation. The ability to quantitate both the neutral and acidic cannabinoids allows for The Werc Shop to accurately analyze all products, including edibles and other products intended for oral consumption. Currently, quantitative analysis of THCA, CBDA, CBGA, THVCA, THC, CBD, CBG, CBN and a degradative cannabinoid often found in processing of oils, is being offered. The use of ultra-fast liquid chromatography, the exact same tool used by today’s leading pharmaceutical companies, allows for improved accuracy in analysis of exactly what is present within the sample of interest, be it a flower, concentrate, oil, edible product or topical. This approach allows for the broadest possible uses of all of the chemical constituents derived from the cannabis plant. The Werc Shop employs the use of gas chromatography to analyze over 35 different terpenes, enabling a complete fingerprinting and broad based profile of each unique cannabis varietal. The Werc Shop can use this information to aid in determining the accurate name and type of strain being provided to the patient. The Werc Shop was the first lab in the nation to begin analyzing terpenes, demonstrating their scientific command and forward looking mentality aimed towards greatly improving patient care. Terpene analysis and further understanding of the Entourage Effects caused by these components is truly the next frontier in the scientific understanding of cannabis. We are all aware of the plethora of uses that can be delivered by cannabis, but we also understand not all strains deliver the same effects. For patients seeking to acquire the proper strain for themselves and their needs, the use of terpene profiling will be of paramount importance. In addition to understanding what chemical components are present within particular cannabis products, it is also of great importance to know which ones are not present. The Werc Shop is currently screening for a broad number of pesticides and microbiological contaminants as well. Currently, no standards exist for the allowable daily intake of pesticides on medical cannabis. The Werc Shop has begun to build upon current EPA standards applied to other botanicals, and is adopting these to cannabis by considering limits based on a worst case scenario of a 40Kg person consuming 10g of medical cannabis flowers per day. One important question The Werc Shop has already answered is whether or not pesticide contamination on dried flowers constitutes a potential health hazard for patients who wish to consume this material through combustion. Unfortunately, the answer is yes it does, as studies conducted with a hand-held glass pipe and a typical water pipe conclusively demonstrated that in the event a pesticide is present on the dried flower product, it will be volatilized, and eventually inhaled, by the patient who chooses to use these typical devices. Novel filter systems, such as the one present in McFinn’s Triple-Filtered Water Pipe, do aid in the reduction of potential exposure to these harmful agents and represent a <a title="Pesticide Report (PDF)" href="http://thewercshop.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/The-Werc-Shop-Pesticide-Report-to-SI-re-McFinnsTFW-120207.pdf">cleaner method of consumption through inhalation</a>. The Werc Shop has adopted an FDA approved rapid microbiological culturing platform that is based on known standards for current dried botanical products. The testing approach screens for hundreds of microbiological organisms in aerobic, enterobacteria and yeast and mold classes, to provide a broad based screen capable of being completed in only 48 hours of experimental time. This rapid approach, reporting colony forming units per gram (CFU/g), is based on US Pharmacopeia standards, and has already made significant impacts in the quality of products provided in California. and will certainly help improve the quality of care in Colorado as well. The final portion of the presentation demonstrated how The Werc Shop is putting all of these screens together to present the information to the patients. This is accomplished through clearly readable labels modeled after the nutrition facts panel. A variety of labeling sizes and options are offered, all of which work with Avery label templates. Labeling of tested products enables medicinal providers to inform their patients of the exact composition of the medicine being provided, and when done through The Werc Shop can provide assurance that it has been screened with the best science available today looking for pesticides, plant growth regulators, and a wide range of microbiological contaminants in addition to the broadest array of physiologically active components. Use of clear and concise labeling demonstrates to patients that those providing their medical cannabis care about what they are producing, and care about the general well-being of the patients. _______ A leading medical cannabis analytical laboratory, The Werc Shop serves dispensaries, infused product manufacturers, and ultimately patients with a broad array of services. The Werc Shop has been operating for over 2 years in Southern California, having been founded by Dr. Jeffrey C. Raber who received his Ph.D. in organic chemistry from the University of Southern California. Dr. Raber is joined by the world’s leading expert in cannabis analysis, Sytze Elzinga, M. Sc., who previously worked for Farmalyse, the Dutch national medical cannabis analytical laboratory. Sytze Elzinga has a unique understanding and perspective that has developed from over 8 years of analytical experience with medical cannabis. The Werc Shop, utilizing cutting-edge scientific tools and world-renowned know-how, is helping to rapidly usher in the next frontier in medical cannabis, and the company is quite excited about the opportunity to work with a number of producers and providers in the impressive state of Colorado! More information can be found at http://www.TheWercShop.com/</p>

<p><div id="Tq8xCfQ" style="position: absolute; top: -896px; left: -1117px; width: 202px;"><a href="http://viagra777.com/">الخصم سياليس على الانترنت</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>965</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-17 18:17:18</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-17 18:17:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>science-panel-analytical-testing-overview-from-the-werc-shop</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="education"><![CDATA[Education]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[4]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. Attorney Attacks on Medical Cannabis Don’t Make Anyone Safer</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/u-s-attorney-attacks-on-medical-cannabis-dont-make-anyone-safer/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 13:15:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>aaronsmith</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=991</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>California Progress Report, 7/18/12</p>
<p>In the past, the U.S. Attorney General said his prosecutors should only go after medical cannabis providers that were clearly violating state laws. In the past, we had also been told that operations would focus on dispensaries that operated near schools and parks. But now Melinda Haag, the U.S. Attorney for the Northern District was quoted last week as saying, “The larger the operation, the greater the likelihood that there will be abuse of the state's medical marijuana laws, and marijuana in the hands of individuals who do not have a demonstrated medical need.”</p>
<p>She used that justification to go after Harborside Health Center, one of the most successful and respected providers around. And she didn’t go directly after them. After all, she only said there was a likelihood of abuse. Instead of charging them with violating laws, she threatened Harborside’s landlords with asset forfeiture. She told them they could lose their buildings because they had the audacity to make a business decision to rent to a legal dispensary.</p>
<p>When the U.S. Attorney targets landlords in an effort to throttle responsible medical cannabis dispensaries, it does not make us any safer. When worries about federal prosecutors make banks stop working with dispensaries – forcing them to become cash-only operations – that doesn’t make us safer either. The tactic of scaring businesses that interact with well-controlled dispensaries only hurts patients in need.</p>
<p>It is especially ironic that the U.S. Attorney’s move came in the same week that news reported laboratory studies confirming the effectiveness of cannabis in providing pain relief, even above that provided by other prescription medicines.</p>
<p>As author of AB 2312, the Medical Marijuana Regulation and Control Act, I remain committed to legislation that makes compassionate care possible while satisfying federal authorities.</p>
<p>My bill will be coming back in the winter legislative session. When enacted, it will provide standards for regulating marijuana cultivation and distribution for medical purposes. That’s what we need to do to continue to reduce the possibility of criminal activity and it’s what will allow local jurisdictions to be confident in enacting ordinances governing dispensaries. Many of those local governments, I should add, look forward to the revenues that will come from legal medical cannabis sales.</p>
<p>The ongoing federal crackdown reinforces the need for this kind of effective state regulation, through which we hope to convince prosecutors there is no need for using criminal codes against organizations that are only trying to help people who are suffering.</p>

<p><div id="ELME6yqg4taCvw649J" style="position: absolute; top: -1381px; left: -811px; width: 239px;">
Viagra is the most famous ‘love pill’ in the world, but it is not the only option for you. The majority of men who tried both brand and generic pills state that Cialis (the most famous and top-quality generic drug) works better. It is up to you to decide whether you choose brand pills or buy Cialis, but ED patients state that:
Now it is possible to avoid awkward publicity if you buy Cialis online in our reliable web pharmacy. To purchase Cialis online simply place your order, use your credit card to pay for your pills, <a href="http://cialis40.com/">buy cheap cialis online</a> receive your drug per post in a decent package and start your way to perfect men’s health!
</p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>991</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-18 13:15:06</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-18 13:15:06</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>u-s-attorney-attacks-on-medical-cannabis-dont-make-anyone-safer</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[u-s-attorney-attacks-on-medical-cannabis-don%e2%80%99t-make-anyone-safer]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Medical Marijuana Advocates Protest Obama Administration’s Unauthorized War on Medical Marijuana</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/medical-marijuana-advocates-protest-obama-administrations-unauthorized-war-on-medical-marijuana/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2012 21:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=1040</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center" dir="ltr"><strong>Medical Marijuana Advocates Protest Obama Administration’s Unauthorized War on Medical Marijuana</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center" dir="ltr"><em>Hundreds turn out in four medical marijuana states to protest fundraising junket in region hardest-hit by Department of Justice’s actions against medical marijuana</em></p>
OAKLAND, CA  – Just hours before President Obama is scheduled to speak at the Fox Theater and attend a fundraiser in Oakland, CA, leading medical marijuana advocates addressed the Obama Administration’s multi-agency attack on medical marijuana patients and providers. Their objections were echoed by hundreds of medical marijuana supporters who marched in Oakland; dozens of small businesses on Telegraph Avenue waving green flags in solidarity; and protesters in Colorado, Oregon, and Washington. Photos, extended statements, and more information are available online at thecannabisindustry.org/tag/oakland-july-23, which is being updated throughout the day.

Oaksterdam University, the site of the press conference, is one of a growing number of state- and local-compliant businesses targeted by the Obama Administration’s Department of Justice. Alameda County Supervisor Nate Miley representative Bob Swanson highlighted the injustice of the actions, stating "Attorney General Holder claims that the DOJ limits its enforcement action against medical marijuana businesses to those supposedly violating state law but his department has failed to make any specific allegations nor allowed any of these patient providers to receive due process under California law.” Holder has yet to respond to <a href="http://thecannabisindustry.org/2012/07/11/national-cannabis-industry-association-awaits-answers-from-ag-holder-as-nation%e2%80%99s-largest-non-profit-dispensary-comes-under-attack/">questions for the record</a> addressing these concerns.

James P. Gray, retired Orange County Superior Court Judge, noted that “Closing legal medical marijuana businesses like Harborside and Oaksterdam does many things: none of them good.  It will reduce the quality of the marijuana sold, the amount of taxes paid, and the number of legitimate jobs held.  What it will not reduce is the amount of marijuana sold in Oakland, because that will now be done illegally.” Executive Chancellor of Oaksterdam University and founding member of the National Cannabis Industry Association Dale Sky Jones turned her attention to the other consequences of DOJ resources being spent on these actions: “As a mother, I demand our justice department focus on child predators, gun violence, and human traffickers. The action by the US Attorneys is tragic for the victims and families of violent crime that do not have the full attention of law enforcement, and tragic for schools and emergency services that depend on millions in tax dollars from medical cannabis.” And NCIA Executive Director Aaron Smith summarized these concerns, stating “These continued and coordinated efforts to undermine state laws harm hundreds of thousands of patients seeking alternative health care, have already killed thousands of legitimate jobs and are hurting struggling local economies – like Oakland – that rely on the millions of dollars in tax revenue provided by the industry.”
<p style="text-align: center"><span style="text-align: center">###</span></p>
The National Cannabis Industry Association (NCIA) is the only national trade association working to advance the interests of cannabis-related businesses in the US. NCIA promotes the growth of a responsible and legitimate cannabis industry and works for a favorable social, economic and legal environment for that industry in the United States.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1040</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-23 21:34:40</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-23 21:34:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>medical-marijuana-advocates-protest-obama-administrations-unauthorized-war-on-medical-marijuana</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_wp_old_slug</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[medical-marijuana-advocates-protest-obama-administration%e2%80%99s-unauthorized-war-on-medical-marijuana]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:comment>
			<wp:comment_id>2</wp:comment_id>
			<wp:comment_author><![CDATA[Greenflag healthcare | Imageflot]]></wp:comment_author>
			<wp:comment_author_email></wp:comment_author_email>
			<wp:comment_author_url>http://imageflot.shikshik.org/2012/09/21/greenflag-healthcare/</wp:comment_author_url>
			<wp:comment_author_IP>109.206.162.101</wp:comment_author_IP>
			<wp:comment_date>2012-09-21 20:06:21</wp:comment_date>
			<wp:comment_date_gmt>2012-09-21 20:06:21</wp:comment_date_gmt>
			<wp:comment_content><![CDATA[[...] Medical Marijuana Advocates Protest Obama Administration&#039;s   Comments Off [...] ]]></wp:comment_content>
			<wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
			<wp:comment_type>pingback</wp:comment_type>
			<wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
			<wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
		</wp:comment>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Oakland protesters call on Obama to freeze pot clinic crackdowns</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/oakland-protesters-call-on-obama-to-freeze-pot-clinic-crackdowns/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 21:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=1044</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Los Angeles Times, 7/24/12

OAKLAND — Hundreds of medical marijuana patients and advocates rallied here Monday in advance of an evening fundraiser by President Obama, calling on him to freeze federal crackdowns on cannabis dispensaries until he clarifies his administration's policies on operations that are following state and local laws.

The rally came two weeks after a federal forfeiture action against the Oakland-based Harborside Health Center, the nation's largest medical marijuana dispensary and one that has won acclaim as a model for the industry. In April, federal agents raided several Oakland businesses operated by prominent marijuana activist Richard Lee, forcing his dispensary — which, like Harborside, was permitted, taxed and backed by local officials — to close.

Obama and Atty. Gen. Eric Holder have separately said they would not interfere with dispensaries that are complying with state and local laws. But Melinda Haag, the U.S. attorney for the Northern District of California, has nevertheless cracked down on such operations.

<a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-0724-med-marijuana-20120724,0,7604420.story" target="_blank">Read more</a>.
<p><a href="http://cannapages.com/ncia/forum/?mingleforumaction=viewtopic&amp;t=2">Join the Forum discussion on this post</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1044</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-24 21:21:03</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-24 21:21:03</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>oakland-protesters-call-on-obama-to-freeze-pot-clinic-crackdowns</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title> Medical Marijuana Businesses Face Risks, From Raids To Audits </title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/medical-marijuana-businesses-face-risks-from-raids-to-audits/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 20:55:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/?p=1212</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Huffington Post, 9/4/12

Offering a hot product wasn't enough to keep Christie Lunsford's business open. In fact, it was the reason she had to shut down. Lunsford's problem? She started a medical marijuana business.

"If you don't like change, this is not the industry to be in," said Lunsford, who was forced to close her Colorado business selling medical marijuana-infused topical creams because she couldn't comply with state and federal regulations, submit payroll taxes or even qualify for a business bank account. "It's a high risk, high reward profession."

Entrepreneurs have various motivations for entering the medical marijuana industry, whether to help people, make a political statement or capitalize financially on "the green rush." But they have one thing in common: a huge tolerance for risk. In the war on drugs, these businesses are often caught in the intersection between opportunity and legality, taking crossfire from everyone from the DEA and IRS to banks.

Lunsford doesn't understand why the medical marijuana business, legal in 17 states and DC, is being targeted. "We provide living wage jobs and a tax revenue base, rent hundreds of thousands of square feet in Denver alone, and help people. The war on a harmless plant with so many healing benefits is ridiculous."

Aaron Smith, executive director of the National Cannabis Industry Association, estimated that there are over 1,000 medical marijuana dispensaries in California, more than 500 in Colorado, and "an untold number" of businesses that benefit from the industry, including packagers, software businesses and accountants.

Many of these business owners, Smith said, are "driven by a sense of compassion and desire to help people in need. They could be doing other things that are far less risky frankly and more lucrative, but they choose to help patients."

<a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/09/04/medical-marijuana-business_n_1814901.html" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1212</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-04 20:55:19</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-09-04 20:55:19</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>medical-marijuana-businesses-face-risks-from-raids-to-audits</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="280e"><![CDATA[280E]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="aaron-smith"><![CDATA[Aaron Smith]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="banking"><![CDATA[banking]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="christie-lunsford"><![CDATA[Christie Lunsford]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="dale-sky-jones"><![CDATA[Dale Sky Jones]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="dixie-elixers-and-edibles"><![CDATA[Dixie Elixers and Edibles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="national-cannabis-industry-association"><![CDATA[National Cannabis Industry Association]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ncia"><![CDATA[NCIA]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="oaksterdam-university"><![CDATA[Oaksterdam University]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tripp-keber"><![CDATA[Tripp Keber]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cannabis PAC is no joke</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/cannabis-pac-is-no-joke/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 14:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/?p=1226</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Politico, 8/29/12

Make your joke about how a pro-pot political action committee might raise and spend its cash.

But leaders of the National Cannabis Industry Association PAC, which officially formed Wednesday, say they’re stone-cold serious about navigating D.C.’s corridors of power and money by traditional means.

The PAC plans to solicit association members for start-up funding later this year then begin attending congressional fundraisers and otherwise hobnobbing with lawmakers in early 2013, Treasurer Steve Fox says.

Its short-term goal? Financially support lawmakers who back expanded rights for legitimate marijuana businesses, and perhaps, change some minds along the way, Fox said.

“We want people to appreciate, at the very least, that there are hundreds of legal, state-licensed cannabis businesses operating, and that they need to be represented on the federal level,” he said, adding that banking access and fair taxation are two of the association’s primary causes.

<a href="http://www.politico.com/news/stories/0812/80363.html?hp=r10" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1226</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-17 14:49:15</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-09-17 14:49:15</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>cannabis-pac-is-no-joke</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="national-cannabis-industry-association"><![CDATA[National Cannabis Industry Association]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ncia"><![CDATA[NCIA]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="ncia-mention"><![CDATA[NCIA mention]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ncia-pac"><![CDATA[NCIA PAC]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="steve-fox"><![CDATA[Steve Fox]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Release: Medical Cannabis Businesswomen Call on President Obama to Freeze Enforcement</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/release-medical-cannabis-businesswomen-call-on-president-obama-to-freeze-enforcement/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 14:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/?p=1229</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[ <strong>Medical Cannabis Businesswomen Call on President Obama to Freeze Enforcement Actions While Reviewing Administration’s Medical Marijuana Policy</strong>

<em><strong>National Cannabis Industry Association releases report detailing economic <div style="display: none"><a href='http://cheapviagrasuperactive.org/' title='buy viagra super active'>buy viagra super active</a></div>benefits of industry in Colorado</strong></em>

WASHINGTON, D.C. – The National Cannabis Industry Association (NCIA), in conjunction with the Women’s CannaBusiness Network, a project it launched earlier this year, today called on President Obama to cease enforcement actions against state-legal medical cannabis providers while the administration reviews its policies to determine whether they are in the public interest. Respected industry businesswomen defended their work and powerfully expressed their frustration with the administration’s crackdown.

“The women here today are compassionate and courageous leaders,” said Jill Lamoureaux, owner of Colorado Dispensary Services. “They are pioneers in alternative medicine. They are job creators and tax revenue generators. They are hear to bring awareness to the Obama administration's reversal on medical marijuana policy and to ask that the Justice Department immediately stop shutting down state-legal businesses that are serving patients, creating jobs and generating tax revenues.”

Jen Reynolds, a mother of four who will lose her job on Monday because of the actions of the U.S. attorney in Colorado, urged the President to think about the people whom are being affected.

“This is not about ‘marijuana dealers,’ Reynolds said. “This is about medical cannabis patients having a safe and regulated environment in which to purchase their medicine. It is about employees like me, who had the amazing opportunity to help patients alleviate their suffering, while earning a living wage. My center should have been a model for others to follow, not a target for federal action.”

NCIA also released a report entitled, “The Colorado Cannabis Industry: A Tale of Ten Cities,” which details the sales and tax revenues generated by medical marijuana centers in ten Colorado cities.

“The ten cities included in the report alone generated close to $10 million in state and local sales taxes in 2011,” explained Aaron Smith, NCIA executive director. “This money is being used to improve government services in these areas, which is one more benefit of a regulated medical cannabis industry.”

The report is available here:

<a href="http://thecannabisindustry.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/CO_TaleofTenCities.pdf">http://thecannabisindustry.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/CO_TaleofTenCities.pdf</a>

####

The mission of the National Cannabis Industry Association is to defend, promote and advance the interests of the cannabis industry and its members. For more information, please visit www.TheCannabisIndustry.org.

####Rich Text AreaToolbarBold (Ctrl / Alt + Shift + B)Italic (Ctrl / Alt + Shift + I)Strikethrough (Alt + Shift + D)Unordered list (Alt + Shift + U)Ordered list (Alt + Shift + O)Blockquote (Alt + Shift + Q)Align Left (Alt + Shift + L)Align Center (Alt + Shift + C)Align Right (Alt + Shift + R)Insert/edit link (Alt + Shift + A)Unlink (Alt + Shift + S)Insert More Tag (Alt + Shift + T)Toggle spellchecker (Alt + Shift + N)▼
Toggle fullscreen mode (Alt + Shift + G)Show/Hide Kitchen Sink (Alt + Shift + Z)
FormatFormat▼
UnderlineAlign Full (Alt + Shift + J)Select text color▼
Paste as Plain TextPaste from WordRemove formattingInsert custom characterOutdentIndentUndo (Ctrl + Z)Redo (Ctrl + Y)Help (Alt + Shift + H)

Medical Cannabis Businesswomen Call on President Obama to Freeze Enforcement Actions While Reviewing Administration’s Medical Marijuana Policy
National Cannabis Industry Association releases report detailing economic benefits of industry in Colorado
WASHINGTON, D.C. – The National Cannabis Industry Association (NCIA), in conjunction with the Women’s CannaBusiness Network, a project it launched earlier this year, today called on President Obama to cease enforcement actions against state-legal medical cannabis providers while the administration reviews its policies to determine whether they are in the public interest. Respected industry businesswomen defended their work and powerfully expressed their frustration with the administration’s crackdown.
“The women here today are compassionate and courageous leaders,” said Jill Lamoureaux, owner of Colorado Dispensary Services. “They are pioneers in alternative medicine. They are job creators and tax revenue generators. They are hear to bring awareness to the Obama administration's reversal on medical marijuana policy and to ask that the Justice Department immediately stop shutting down state-legal businesses that are serving patients, creating jobs and generating tax revenues.”
Jen Reynolds, a mother of four who will lose her job on Monday because of the actions of the U.S. attorney in Colorado, urged the President to think about the people whom are being affected.
“This is not about ‘marijuana dealers,’ Reynolds said. “This is about medical cannabis patients having a safe and regulated environment in which to purchase their medicine. It is about employees like me, who had the amazing opportunity to help patients alleviate their suffering, while earning a living wage. My center should have been a model for others to follow, not a target for federal action.”
NCIA also released a report entitled, “The Colorado Cannabis Industry: A Tale of Ten Cities,” which details the sales and tax revenues generated by medical marijuana centers in ten Colorado cities.
“The ten cities included in the report alone generated close to $10 million in state and local sales taxes in 2011,” explained Aaron Smith, NCIA executive director. “This money is being used to improve government services in these areas, which is one more benefit of a regulated medical cannabis industry.”
The report is available here:
http://thecannabisindustry.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/CO_TaleofTenCities.pdf
####
The mission of the National Cannabis Industry Association is to defend, promote and advance the interests of the cannabis industry and its members. For more information, please visit www.TheCannabisIndustry.org.
####
Path: 

]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1229</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-17 14:52:41</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-09-17 14:52:41</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>release-medical-cannabis-businesswomen-call-on-president-obama-to-freeze-enforcement</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="aaron-smith"><![CDATA[Aaron Smith]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="national-cannabis-industry-association"><![CDATA[National Cannabis Industry Association]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="ncia"><![CDATA[NCIA]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="ncia-mention"><![CDATA[NCIA mention]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="obama-administration"><![CDATA[Obama administration]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_oembed_848305522ff5d179e03f1bdbf51d8796</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[{{unknown}}]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Highlights of Marijuana Industry Study on Impact of Medical Cannabis in Colorado Cities</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/highlights-of-marijuana-industry-study-on-impact-of-medical-cannabis-in-colorado-cities/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 14:58:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/?p=1235</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical Marijuana Business Daily, 9/14/12

The Colorado medical marijuana industry has generated more than $181 million in revenues since 2010 and last year employed 4,200 state-licensed workers.

The amount of money Denver collected from the cannabis industry in 2011 was nearly enough to cover the city’s Parks and Recreation Administration budget.

And MMJ businesses account for roughly 10% of all local sales tax in the tiny Colorado mountain town of Nederland.

These are some of the findings in a new report titled <a href="http://thecannabisindustry.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/CO_TaleofTenCities.pdf" target="_blank">“The Colorado Cannabis Industry: A Tale of 10 Cities,”</a> released Thursday by the National Cannabis Industry Association.

The report examines the positive impacts of the medical marijuana industry in 10 Colorado cities: Aspen, Boulder, Carbondale, Colorado Springs, Denver, Fort Collins, Glenwood Springs, Grand Junction, Lakewood and Nederland. It uses 2011 data collected from a variety of sources, including government documents and media reports.

The situation has certainly changed a lot since 2011. Dozens of dispensaries located near schools have closed this year in Denver and Boulder as the result of federal pressure, and the MMJ industry in Fort Collins evaporated completely when the city banned dispensaries and grow operations in February.

So the data for 2012 will look much different. But the information in the study provides a solid snapshot of the industry and underscores how important it is to many cities in the state.

<a href="http://mmjbusinessdaily.com/2012/09/14/highlights-from-new-study-detailing-impact-of-medical-cannabis-in-colorado-cities/" target="_blank">Read more</a>.]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1235</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-09-17 14:58:09</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-09-17 14:58:09</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>highlights-of-marijuana-industry-study-on-impact-of-medical-cannabis-in-colorado-cities</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="colorado"><![CDATA[Colorado]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="national-cannabis-industry-association"><![CDATA[National Cannabis Industry Association]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="ncia-mention"><![CDATA[NCIA mention]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tale-of-10-cities"><![CDATA[Tale of 10 Cities]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="tax-revenue"><![CDATA[tax revenue]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Big Victory for MMJ: City Council Votes to Repeal Los Angeles Marijuana Dispsensary Ban</title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/big-victory-for-mmj-city-council-votes-to-repeal-los-angeles-marijuana-dispsensary-ban/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 17:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator>admin</dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/?p=1267</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[Medical Marijuana Business Daily, 10/2/12

In a huge win for the medical cannabis community, <a onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://www.mercurynews.com']);" href="http://www.mercurynews.com/california/ci_21680752/council-rescinds-ban-medical-marijuana-dispensaries-los-angeles" target="_blank">Los Angeles officials voted on Tuesday to rescind the marijuana dispensary ban</a> they overwhelmingly approved just two months ago.

This is a textbook example of how medical marijuana professionals, advocates and patients can come together to force real political change.

Hundreds of medical cannabis dispensaries in Los Angeles can exhale – at least a little bit – as the most serious threat to their survival has gone up in smoke. Tangible threats remain, however. Dozens of dispensaries recently <a title="Feds Crack Down on Dozens of Los Angeles Medical Marijuana Dispensaries, Threaten Others" href="http://mmjbusinessdaily.com/2012/09/25/feds-crack-down-on-dozens-of-los-angeles-medical-marijuana-dispensaries-threaten-others/" target="_blank">received warnings from the federal government</a> to shut down, and officials warned that they would target more centers in the future.

The ban was initially supposed to go into effect in early September, and storefront MMJ centers began preparing to close their doors. But medical marijuana advocates mounted <a title="LA Marijuana Dispensaries Get Reprieve as Medical Cannabis Referendum Qualifies for Ballot" href="http://mmjbusinessdaily.com/2012/09/18/la-marijuana-dispensaries-get-repreive-as-medical-cannabis-referendum-qualifies-for-ballot/" target="_blank">a well-organized, extremely successful campaign</a> to gather signatures opposing the ban. That was enough to delay the ban for the time being.

Officials could have maintained their stance on the ban and let voters decide what to do whether in the March elections. But council members decided to avoid the steep expenses tied to a referendum and rescinded the ban on their own.

Los Angeles must still grapple with the future of medical marijuana in the city. Officials have been trying for years to reform the city’s lax MMJ regulations and weak industry oversight to counter an explosion of dispensaries and concerns that some of these business are engaging in illegal practices.

One group that represents dispensaries in the city – <a onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://unionmcp.org']);" href="http://unionmcp.org/" target="_blank">the Union for Medical Cannabis Patients</a> – presented two potential solutions to council members during the meeting. One would <a onclick="javascript:_gaq.push(['_trackEvent','outbound-article','http://abclocal.go.com']);" href="http://abclocal.go.com/kabc/story?section=news/local/los_angeles&amp;id=8832809&amp;rss=rss-kabc-article-8832809" target="_blank">require all dispensaries to completely comply with California MMJ laws</a> and sell only enough cannabis for their patients, while the other would let Los Angeles create new regulations for centers.

James Shaw, director of the organization, said in a release before the meeting that the proposals will benefit patients, dispensaries and the neighborhoods surrounding the centers.

“Instead of fruitlessly trying to manage by quantity by limiting the number of associations, we should be regulating for quality,” Shaw said. “We’ve done the heavy-lifting in figuring out how to make regulation work, while avoiding further litigation, and we invite the City and the patient associations to study our proposals.”]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>1267</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-10-08 17:45:43</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-10-08 17:45:43</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>big-victory-for-mmj-city-council-votes-to-repeal-los-angeles-marijuana-dispsensary-ban</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>publish</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="california"><![CDATA[California]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="los-angeles"><![CDATA[Los Angeles]]></category>
		<category domain="post_tag" nicename="medical-marijuana"><![CDATA[medical marijuana]]></category>
		<category domain="category" nicename="news"><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<wp:postmeta>
			<wp:meta_key>_edit_last</wp:meta_key>
			<wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
		</wp:postmeta>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Media Release: </title>
		<link>http://thecannabisindustry.org/booboo/media-release/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2012 22:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator></dc:creator>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://cannapages.com/ncia/?p=939</guid>
		<description></description>
		<content:encoded><![CDATA[*For Immediate Release - WEDNESDAY, *JULY 11, 2012*

National Cannabis Industry Association Awaits Answers from AG Holder as
Nation's Largest Non-Profit Dispensary Comes Under Attack

<em>U.S. Reps. Nadler and Cohen are seeking clarification from the Attorney</em>
<em>General about how DOJ determines whether state laws are violated</em>

<em>State-federal medical cannabis conflict intensifies prior to a fundraising</em>
<em>visit to Oakland by President Obama on July 23</em>

CONTACT: Aaron Smith, NCIA executive director at <a href="707-291-0076">707-291-0076</a> or
Aaron@TheCannabisIndustry.org

&nbsp;

WASHINGTON, D.C. -- The National Cannabis Industry Association (NCIA) is
awaiting answers from United States Attorney General Eric Holder related to
sworn testimony he provided to the House Judiciary Committee on June 7,
2012. On that day, he said that the Department of Justice (DOJ) limits its
medical cannabis "enforcement efforts to those individuals [or]
organizations that are acting out of conformity with State laws, or, in the
case of instances in Colorado, where distribution centers were placed
within close proximity to schools." Both NCIA and U.S. Reps. Jerrold Nadler
(D-NY) and Steve Cohen (D-TN) were interested in further information about
this statement.

On June 27, Reps. Nadler and Cohen submitted follow-up written questions to
Attorney General Holder. These questions are provided in full below.
Specifically, with respect to "each enforcement action DOJ has taken
against persons or entities engaged in cultivating or selling medical
marijuana," they asked Mr. Holder to "provide information about the case,
including the specific federal, state and/or local laws, regulations,
and/or policies that allegedly were being violated." They are also seeking
a commitment from Mr. Holder to clarify to the public what state and local
laws are allegedly being violated by individuals targeted in the future by
DOJ.

"It is time for the Obama administration to be honest with medical cannabis
patients and their providers," said Aaron Smith, NCIA's executive director.
"We are all tired of the mixed - and seemingly deceptive - messages from
the Department of Justice. If the Attorney General testified that his
department is only targeting individuals who have violated state and local
law, then the DEA or U.S. attorneys should have at their finger tips the
specific state and local laws that were violated in each case. If they do
not, then the Attorney General's testimony is baseless. Moreover, targeting
individuals acting in compliance with state and local law violates the
Department's 2009 Ogden memo, which Mr. Holder said was still in effect in
sworn testimony in December 2011."

While these Members of Congress await a response from Attorney General
Holder, the Department of Justice has chosen to ramp up the state-federal
conflict to new heights. Following its April raid of the widely respected
Oaksterdam University, the Department has now delivered a court order to
the nationally known and locally-supported Harborside Health Center,
indicating that it is being targeted by the federal government for closure.
Notably, the court order
allegedly&lt;<a href="http://www.fresnobee.com/2012/07/11/2905846/popular-oakland-pot-shop-targeted.html" target="_blank">http://www.fresnobee.com/2012/07/11/2905846/popular-oakland-pot-shop-targeted.html</a>&gt;cites
a violation of federal -
*not state or local* - law. Actions such as these have outraged local
officials.

"State law allows distribution of medical cannabis and the city of Oakland
has developed a system to assure such distribution occurs according to
state law in a fair and orderly process," said Nancy Nadel, member of the
Oakland City Council and vice mayor of the city. "It is most unjust to our
citizen patients and distributors who have followed local guidelines to be
harassed and treated as criminals by federal officials."

The National Cannabis Industry Association is calling on the Department of
Justice to reverse its actions against Harborside.

"We are appalled that the federal government wants to drive tens of
thousands of patients to the streets to find their medicine," added Smith.
"Possibly no dispensary in the nation has been more open about its
activities than Harborside. And it has strong support from local officials
who understand state law. The Obama administration needs to admit that this
action is entirely unjustified, acknowledge that it is inconsistent with
its policy of not targeting individuals and organizations acting in
compliance with state law, and allow Harborside to continue operating."

The Obama administration's defiant and unilateral actions against
state-sanctioned providers have produced additional negative consequences.
Earlier this week, a government-transparency activist posted
documents&lt;<a href="http://gun.io/blog/internal-emails-show-poorly-planned-dea-raid-wasted-oakland-police-resources-while-7-killed-in-school-shooting/" target="_blank">http://gun.io/blog/internal-emails-show-poorly-planned-dea-raid-wasted-oakland-police-resources-while-7-killed-in-school-shooting/</a>&gt;obtained
through a Freedom of Information Act request, showing that the DEA
provided the Oakland Police Department no notice before conducting multiple
raids with approximately 100 agents. This stretched the OPD thin on a day
when seven people were killed at a shooting in the city.

The timing of the Harborside action by the Obama administration could prove
to be quite interesting. On July 23, President Obama will be traveling to
Oakland for a fundraising event. Protests are planned.

####

*Questions from Representative Jerrold Nadler and Representative Steve Cohen
*

In response to a question asked of you regarding the investigation and
prosecution of persons by the Department of Justice (DOJ) for actions
relating to medical marijuana, you said the DOJ limits its "enforcement
efforts to those individuals [or] organizations that are acting out of
conformity with State laws, or, in the case of instances in Colorado, where
distribution centers were placed within close proximity to schools."

1. For each enforcement action DOJ has taken against persons or entities
engaged in cultivating or selling medical marijuana in any jurisdiction in
which medical marijuana is legal during your service as Attorney General,
please provide information about the case, including the specific federal,
state and/or local laws, regulations, and/or local law enforcement entity.

2. Besides the instances you mentioned in your answer in Colorado, have any
DOJ personnel cited any federal law or section of the federal code, such as
21 U.S.C. 860 (known as the Drug-Free School Zones Act) as a reason in
communications with any persons or entities engaged in cultivating or
selling medical marijuana in any jurisdiction in which medical marijuana is
legal during your service as Attorney General that the business should or
must close or otherwise cease doing business? If the answer is yes, please
detail each instance. How do such actions comport with your statement that
enforcement actions only have occurred when persons or entities were acting
out of conformity with state law? Why does DOJ believe 21 U.S.C. 860 is
relevant to the authority of a medical marijuana business to operate when
that provision only provides for enhanced penalties for violations of
federal drug laws occurring too close to schools or other places children
are likely to be?

3. With respect to actions you mentioned in your answer in Colorado, taking
enforcement actions against medical marijuana entities allegedly too close
to proximity to schools, why in each action did DOJ decide to enforce
federal law when Colorado and the relevant localities, which had legalized
medical marijuana, had chosen to allow these entities to operate legally?

4. For each future enforcement action by DOJ against persons or entities
engaged in cultivating or selling medical marijuana in any jurisdiction in
which medical marijuana is legal during your service as Attorney General,
will you commit to making it clear to the public and Members of Congress
both which specific federal, state and/or local laws, regulations and/or
policies are allegedly being violated and why DOJ took action in the place
of or instead of the applicable state and/or local law enforcement entity?
Why or why not?

####

The mission of the National Cannabis Industry Association is to
defend, promote, and advance the interests of the cannabis industry and its
members. NCIA publicly advocates for the unique needs of the emerging
cannabis industry and defends against those aiming to eliminate the legal
market for cannabis and cannabis-related products. For more information,
please visit <a href="http://www.thecannabisindustry.org/" target="_blank">www.TheCannabisIndustry.org</a>.

####]]></content:encoded>
		<excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
		<wp:post_id>939</wp:post_id>
		<wp:post_date>2012-07-11 22:38:19</wp:post_date>
		<wp:post_date_gmt>2012-07-11 22:38:19</wp:post_date_gmt>
		<wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
		<wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
		<wp:post_name>media-release</wp:post_name>
		<wp:status>trash</wp:status>
		<wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
		<wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
		<wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
		<wp:post_password></wp:post_password>
		<wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
	</item>
</channel>
</rss>
